Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome back to This weekend's ask
show the first one of this weekend. This
is episode 326. Today we discuss
geopolitics and history. I will take
questions you all have asked in the
comments. And before we do that, let's
see who all is there on the live chat. I
can see Shri Rama Chandraa Namaha. Thank
you sir. Geopolitical Dubai is here from
Indor. Anonymous R7U5T. Good evening. My
actuarial sessions is also here.
Gajapati Dave is here from Odisha. Good
evening Ashwani
Badam
indeed. Thank you Jam ma'am. Mary Kane
hello good to see you ma'am. Uh real
vadirudin Ram everyone GK GK87 good
morning well good morning to you V4 for
valor Ram Ram G u Sumit Agarwal Ram Ram
G indeed uh Omnak Namaskar Shivanch
Swami Aush Singh Praan G uh field strong
man hello hello everybody hello to you
as well Krishna of the Suriname
Netherlands good to see you sir good
evening and good morning wherever you
are uh IPK1s says kouten aband
land to you as well. Geopolitical once
again from Indor Vladimir Putin. Are you
singing? Feel strong man. Swami is here
from Jaipur. GK Namaste G. Sumit 4 Z4
I9X. Namaskar. Anka Kachab. Good evening
ma'am. Nirwana Shanks. Kodi Chiva. Kodi
Chiva. Uh feel strong man once again.
Nabit Tadas. Namaste. Mlevin 69. It's
over Sar. What is overs?
Uh Sid toxicratos, hello. Uh random
skull jri krishna indeed. Patilty
namaste g nam ma'am. Bishek shukla live
trump in new epste files. Well yeah well
what can I say? Manhattan nak namaskka
rishikesh das Gupta. Hello Swami 0709
nirvana shanks slash hello
8045. Good evening Amisha Mishra good
evening ma'am. Anime Manish Kardosu.
Namaste ma'am. Namaste. Good to see you
ma'am. Uh Abishekl Shukla live good
evening sir thank you and Abhishekli is
here from Kpur. Uh who else do we have?
Anonymous scientist Bonjour and hello
indeed V for Valor Ash King
2 OP Sedant is here from Mumbai.
Priyanka Javalia Namaskar ma'am. Um
Manhattan Surya Pratab Namaskar from
Bhat real painter.
Okay. Shalom. Shalom. Real painter G.
Uh, CEO of Sigma Grindet. Hello
Manhattan and so many other people. I
won't be able to greet you all
individually. Uh, Honey, where what was
that? Lero online. Good to see you sir.
Good to see you indeed. Uh, Bupes
Condell, hello Raj Rani Joy Singh Balir.
Hello. Bonjour to Sedant from Mumbai.
Geopolitical once again. Who else do we
have?
Uh, Sumit Agarwal, Abhinav Singh, Akash
Banerjee, KJ Wonders and everyone else.
Okay. Uh, Imran is also here. Imran 178.
Good evening, sir. Okay. Uh, anime lover
6 honey badger of Kolinga. Well, that's
great name. Good to see you. Uh, so
anonymous scientist says Epstein files.
Damn.
What can I say? What can I say about
what has come out in the Epstein files?
I mean, it's a who's who of the
fantastic people, the great people of
the United States, a nation that is
ruled by perverts, criminals, and
pedophiles.
The nation that seeks to teach the world
about human rights and democracy and all
that. I mean, see what they have been
exposed doing.
And they're going to continue tomorrow
morning as if nothing's happened. No
one's going to be prosecuted. The same
people are going to continue ruling the
world.
I mean what about Trump? Donald J. Trump
the president of the United States.
Is it allegations we are making here?
It's whatever has been released. I will
not even list out the things I have
read. Makes me want to vomit.
But all of this that's been revealed,
the Epstein files, it has been revealed
by the government of the United States
which reports to Donald J. Trump and
they have exposed him. Not just him,
Bill Gates,
uh the previous presidents, whoever they
are,
uh Shri Elon Musk G, I mean so many of
these people have been exposed. Uh this
this guy this fellow Howard Lutnik creep
monster.
These people are ruling that country.
These are apparently western values.
This is western culture and
civilization.
And they're going to tell us what human
rights are and what democracy is.
They're going to preach to us how to
improve our our backward culture.
You know, moral high ground. That's what
they've always had.
I mean, what are we seeing? The question
is Trump has been thoroughly exposed. It
looks like he has not been totally
exposed this far, apparently. So, why
has his FBI,
his government, why have they released
all this stuff that that exposes Donald
Trump? Is he not in control of the US
government?
Is he not no longer in control of the
FBI?
What's going on? Is somebody else
controlling the US government FBI? Who
knows? These are legitimate questions.
When you had the previous speed
pedophile, Biden who was ruling the
country, he clearly was in no in no
shape to be in control of the of of the
government. Someone's someone was ruling
the government. Someone was running it.
Someone was was operating the government
and and ruling the country.
So, wow. I mean, what are we seeing
here, right?
Yeah. Damn. Indeed. Damn. Okay, let's
get going with the actual questions I've
selected from the comments. What what
what are the questions that we have? Um,
give me a second. Okay, what's the first
question? The first question is by Somi.
Trump's approval rating is at a record
low of 37%.
Uh, IC is terrorizing its own people.
The US economy is not doing well at all.
Even the grocery prices are very high.
Trump hasn't been able to end the Russia
Ukraine war. His tariffs are just passed
on to the American consumers.
Apart from Venezuela, the abduction of
the Venezuelan president and his wife,
and apart from the attack on vocism,
whatever that is, Trump hasn't been able
to achieve anything substantial. Do you
think Trump is a liability to the US
establishment or what is traditionally
called the deep state? Well, first of
all, let us list Trump's achievements or
or nonachchievements thus far. So, if
you remember all of you, while he was
campaigning for the presidency,
Trump repeatedly promised to end the
Russia Ukraine war within 24 hours of
taking office. He even claimed that he
will have it settled possibly before the
inauguration.
Right? It's been over a year that he has
been president. The war is going on. And
no peace deal, comprehensive peace deal
or partial peace deal exists. Nothing
exists.
Terrible failure, miserable failure.
You know, back in the 2000s,
there was a president in the US called
George W. Bush. And those were the the
early days of Google and search engines
and all that. And no one knew what SEO
used to be. No, at that time nobody
understood SEO, search engine
optimization. And there was a time when
if you went to google.com and you and
you typed in miserable failure and hit
enter the first result would be George
W. Bush. So somebody had used SEO
techniques which was a very new set of
techniques at the time, very new concept
to uh you know ensure that Google gave
you George W. Bush as the first search
result when you when you searched for
miserable failure. Well, today's
miserable failure clearly is Donald
Trump. When it comes to the Ukraine,
Russia Ukraine war, he repeatedly
promised he will end the war within 24
hours of taking office. Miserable
failure. What other achievements can
Donald Trump boast of? I mean, he has
successfully undermined decades old
security partnerships with his own
allies, especially Europe, the EU
nations and the NATO nations. He has had
this highly transactional approach.
He's telling each of his allies that you
are a financial burden on me. He has
been giving his allies the third world
treatment that the allies are not
accustomed to. The allies we're talking
about here are the nations that are part
of the EU and NATO. They are used to
being treated as equals by the US. They
know they're not equals in terms of hard
power or whatever. But the the approach,
the treatment is that of equals, right?
Polite, courteous, diplomatic treatment,
respectful treatment and so on. Trump
has been opening openly telling them on
their face that you all are financial
burdens to me. He's been treating them
like third world nations. Well, that's
terribly disrespectful. And Trump's
approach has been incredibly
transactional. He has uh focused. He's
fixated. He's obsessed on short-term
deals. is obsessed on tariffs and public
attacks on all his partners, North
American partners, Central American
partners, uh European partners, whoever.
And uh this has essentially actually had
the effect of increasingly isolating the
US, right? And this approach neglects
the major strategic challenges the the
United States faces. And as we remember
last year, you know, what April or
something, 2025, he imposed the highest
US tariffs since the great depression,
right? And he called the he called this
liberation day. He said that jobs will
come roaring back and factories will
come roaring back to the US. What's
happened
every month after that?
Manufacturing employment steadily fell.
It decreased in the US. So his actions
have had the exact opposite effect
compared to what he had claimed it would
have. And then we have mass
deportations. We have these detention
camps of of people. Humiliating
treatment given to people who are
non-citizens. You know um Trump has
expanded the use of police even soldiers
as immigration enforcers and all the IC
brutality that we are seeing around all
around the place. Right. And Trump has
been trying to uh restrict birthright
citizenship. That's been part of the US
ethos for the longest time. Right?
Birthright citizenship has been what
it's been it's been kind of sacrosanked
in the US. So that he's trying to
restrict. Right? So overall Trump has
been apart from the abduction of Maduro
a miserable failure. I mean look at the
treatment he has meated out to India and
what is the outcome that he has
achieved? India said okay you don't want
to deal with us you want to adopt
maximalist positions we'll go and deal
with the EU with the EU we'll we'll do
trade deals all over the place we'll
just ignore you and the EU has done the
exact same thing the EU went to India
India and the EU have signed the mother
of all trade deals what did Trump
achieve
isolation
Trump is isolating the US the thing is
that nobody can ignore the US it's so
powerful but nobody wants to deal deal
with the US everyone's looking for
alternatives Right.
So that's the situation. I mean,
miserable failure thus far, Trump. So I
is Trump a liability to the deep state?
Well, is he a liability to the deep
state? Uh not thus far.
>> Uh Trump's see why has Trump been
allowed to become president?
He has been allowed to become president
so that he can reshape the global world
order and that he is in the process of
doing. He his job is to acquire for the
US control over all the major energy
exporting nations. He's done that with
Venezuela. He perhaps may do that with
Iran. And the objective is to isolate
nations like China and Russia and even
possibly India and exert more pressure
on them. Hard pressure. You know
when you have a nation like China, when
you have a nation like India, these two
nations depend on
other countries for their energy
supplies and if the US controls all
those countries well then they can exert
tremendous pressure on China and India
so those things he's able to possibly he
could be able to achieve Venezuela
already has happened um he's also cut
off Syria from Russia and China could do
that with Iran possibly so he's doing
all those things but at what cost at the
cost of isolating the US at the cost of
drawing all you know pushing all his
allies away pushing a nation like India
away. India has cultivated a great
relationship with the US over the past
25 years and this guy in a period of a
couple of weeks ended all that. There's
no trust now. India doesn't India simply
can't trust the US anymore after the
their antics during operation and so on.
So overall he's he's doing what he has
been brought in to do but the cost is is
substantial. Maybe the the deep state is
okay with u the cost that the US is is
incurring right now.
Vidyman says if the European Union is
not fully sovereign, how does it have
the authority to negotiate and sign a
trade deal with India? Has the US
exerted any indirect influence in this
process? So I keep saying that the EU
nations aren't really sovereign. Uh they
don't have territorial sovereignty,
right? Because they can't they don't
control their borders. They don't
control who comes in, who goes out,
right? Uh they don't have economic or
financial sovereignty because none of
them have their own currency. They
depend on the the EU on the on the euro,
right? None of them controls the EU. So
they don't they don't have financial
sovereignty. And those of them who are
members of NATO don't even have military
sovereignty because from time to time
their military or parts of their
military come under foreign control.
So clearly the EU nations are not
sovereign entities. But the European
Union as a as a whole is sovereign.
So none of the nations is sovereign. But
the EU as a whole is a sovereign entity.
It controls its territory. It controls
who comes in or goes out of the Shenin
area through visas and all all that
enforcement. It controls its economy. It
has its own currency, the euro. And from
the military perspective, let's keep
that out of the out of the thing because
the EU doesn't really have a proper
military of its own. It depends on NATO
and so on. But apart from that, from the
economic perspective, it is economically
sovereign. So it is economically
sovereign. That's why it has the
authority to negotiate on its own a
trade deal with India and sign this this
said trade deal. Um so that's that's the
situation. It's not like the EU is non-s
sovereign. the individual nations that
make up the European Union, those aren't
sovereign. The EU is indeed economically
or financially sovereign, legislatively
sovereign and territorially sovereign.
Military issue, the military issue is a
whole different story. That's that is
not the thing we're discussing here. Has
the US exerted any indirect influence in
the process? Well, I suppose the US has
not done that thus far, but they may try
and interfere. That's always a
possibility going forward.
Okay, questions about the India EU trade
deal. Real Radi Pudin says, "Is the
India EU trade deal going to have
significant opposition coming from the
US?" Aayush Singh says, "Please share
your analysis of the recent Indo-Uropean
FTA free trade agreement. Who is on more
receiving terms compared to who benefits
more compared to which side benefits
more?" essentially that's what he's
asking. And Rush Tar says, "Your take on
the recent trade deal between India and
the EU. This didn't get coverage due to
other issues in India like the UGC
fiasco etc. But why is it being called
the mother of all trade deals? The US is
upset with Scots Bessant even calling it
hypocrisy. China, Turkey, Bangladesh,
Pakistan are all not not very happy
about this deal. Moreover, we are
signing a framework for a major defense
equipment and intel sharing deal. So h
how is it going to impact our economic
and defense uh standing in the world? So
let's first talk about the economic
aspects of this deal. I mean the deal
that's been signed is the economic deal
the FDA the free trade agreement between
India and the EU. So
what are the contours the parameters and
so on of the FDA between India and the
EU. So this FDA it gives preferential
access or zero duty access to more than
99% of India's exports to the EU by
value. Okay. And this is far far higher
than what India has in uh the other
markets. We have FTS with other markets
like Australia and um the UAE and so on
so forth. Uh but we don't have anything
like this like what we have achieved
with the EU right so EU duties are being
eliminated on about 70% of tariff lines
immediately. So whatever tariff tariff
line is a tariff line is is a set of
tariffs or it's a tariff that's imposed
on a certain category of goods. So you
have a bunch of tariff lines. Okay. So
these duties these tariffs are being
eliminated on about 70% of these tariff
lines uh which cover about 90% of
India's exports
and uh the remaining ones will see
phased cuts. phase by phase the cuts
will happen uh and and uh so that that's
that's one thing about and for the EU so
about 90% of the goods that India is
exporting to the EU will have faced zero
tariffs eventually and the remaining
goods will face about I mean lower
tariffs than what we were facing when it
comes to the EU's goods that they are
exporting to India about 86% maybe
almost 90% of those will see zero
tariffs in The rest will see decreased
tariffs and maybe phased implementation
and so on. For India, you have sectors
like textiles, like pharmaceuticals
uh like uh you know engineering goods uh
agricultural products and so on. These
goods will get almost zero almost
immediate zero tariff or zero duty
access to the European market. And the
EU EU is already India's largest trading
partner in many of these sectors, right?
Uh so that's fantastic and
we're going to get excellent commitments
for
services exports for mobility of skilled
professionals. So Indian skilled
professionals who will get to um will
have easier access to work in in the
European Union, right? And this is
something that India has kind of not
really got other free trade agreements.
So this directly supports the Indian IT
sector, right? Our IT sector mainly
services the US. Now we're going to do
that. We'll have the opportunity to do
this for for Europe also. And the US is
clamping down on immigration and what
not. So it's it's it's harder for Indian
professionals to go and work in the US,
but it's going to be easier now for them
to go and work in the EU. So it's going
to support India's massive IT sector.
It's going to support India's business
services sector. And obviously it'll be
great for highskilled employment in
India. And essentially it it gives India
access to uh 27 nation single market. So
India has 1.4 billion people. The EU has
450 billion pe million people. It brings
together almost almost 2 billion people
in a single market. Right? That's
fantastic. And both nations want to
diversify away from the US and both
nations want to diversify away from
China as well. you know, we don't want
over dependence on China, right? And we
want to hedge against the American
tariff volatility, whichever which you
know, you never know what kind of
tariffs the Americans will push on you
depending on what side of the bed Donald
Trump woke up on today morning, that
sort of thing, right? So, overall, it's
it's great. It's kind of win-win
whatever I've seen thus far. I'm not
doing a detailed pointby-point analysis
here. Um, it's it's a broad analysis I'm
giving you. Uh so see India wants to
become more of a manu manufacturing
power make in India at barbarat all of
that right and a lot of this
manufacturing labor intensive
manufacturing that happens in south in
in East Asia
if if India can capture even a fraction
of that market right and and sell it and
sell the goods tariff-free
in a high income market like the EU view
it's it's going to support making in
India it's going to support Amanda
Bharat it's going to support export-led
growth of the Indian economy and that's
fantastic it's something that no other
single FTA or any other agreement
anywhere else offers for India at this
scale so it's it's massive it's actually
massive for India and uh of course it it
brings India and the EU closer together
this will make it less likely for EU
nations to interfere in India's internal
affairs and mess around with the issues
you know regarding sovereignty or
support Pakistan or support China or
even support the US because they benefit
from a stronger more stable and more
robust and faster growing India
they they benefit directly from this so
why will they do anything to undermine
India right so this strengthens India's
position as a key partner for the
European Union in in the current world
order it it strengthens India's
geopolitical position significantly. It
will reduce India's vulnerability to US
sanctions, US tariffs and India's overd
dependence on the US, right? And and a
and a few Asian markets as well. So it
it diversifies risk for India. It
increases leverage that India has on
various EU nations including diplomatic
leverage and other kinds of leverage.
Right? So overall it's fantastic.
Overall it's great. I'm sure there are
there are some things that need to be
looked looked into and so on. But
overall from a big picture perspective,
it's fantastic. You know, um you could
have uh tens of billions of dollars of
additional exports going on from India,
going from India to the EU. And uh
overall, I I I see that it's it's a
fantastic development for India and for
the EU. Um so I think it's kind of a
win-win situation, right? Uh the US is
upset. Yeah, the US will be upset about
this because you know they thought they
they're going to bring India they're
going to drag India back to the
negotiating table that India is going to
come and say sorry to the US and agree
to the US to the trade deal on American
terms. Well, that's not happening and
India's got this big trade deal with the
EU. We don't need a trade deal with the
US. It can can keep it in the in the
freezer in in deep freeze if they want.
So the Americans are upset and they are
moaning about this and complaining about
the EU and and so on, right? Um bless
calling it hypocrisy. Well, he is the
hypocrite there. Uh China, Turkey,
Bangladesh, Pakistan, not happy. Who
cares? I mean, who cares about Turkey,
Bangladesh, Pakistan, how do they
matter? Insignificant nations. China,
China hasn't said anything about it as
far as I know. Uh you know, China hasn't
expressed displeasure as far as I know.
But yeah, obviously they will not be
very pleased about this. It is what it
is. Um
is the is this trade deal going to have
significant opposition coming from the
US? So this trade deal is signed. The
FDA is signed but it has to be ratified
by both sides. And this process could
take several months. Possibly it could
be operational you know in maybe 6
months maybe by the end of this year. So
it's a process that takes time. Okay.
There's a process it under goes after
the signing.
So in the meanwhile will the Americans
pressurize the EU? They may. I'm sure
they will, but it's not in the EU's
interests to walk away from this trade
deal, you know, or try to dilute it or
whatever. It's not in their interests.
So, I'm sure they'll the Americans will
exert some kind of pressure on it. I'm
sure they will, but I'm pretty sure this
will go ahead.
Um, what about the defense uh
defense framework? Framework for major
defense equipment and intel sharing
deal. Intel sharing is fine.
both sides obviously will curate the
intel they share with each other. So I
don't see any major issues there. When
it comes to defense equipment and all
that, we're going to have to be a little
careful because see our
our strongest
and most time-tested geopolitical
relationship is the one that we have
with Russia. Russia is is a trusted
partner.
India and Russia have never done
anything that significantly
you know undermines the other's
interest. Yeah, there may be some
irritants here and there whatever but
nothing major. India and Russia have no
major disagreements
and the track record is such that we can
trust each other within parameters right
within the parameters of the of each
nation's national interest. So whatever
we do with, let's say, the EU or whoever
else, we will not
do anything that jeopardizes our tried
and tested relationship with Russia, our
privileged strategic partnership with
Russia. We won't do anything that
jeopardizes this. Now, let's say we are
selling defense equipment. It's it's buy
and sell. Obviously, we'll buy stuff,
we'll sell stuff. So, let's say we are
selling defense equipment to the EU
nations. What if it gets used by NATO? I
mean what about that?
What if we sell Akash surfaceto-air
missiles
to the Europeans? The Akash SAM system
performed admirably during Operation
Sundur. It probably it's one of the
components of the best battle tested air
defense system in the world. Better than
the Israeli Iron Dome thus far at this
point. So if we sell that to the
Europeans and what if they use it
against Russia or they what if they
provide it to Ukraine to use against
Russia. I mean those are the things that
we'll have to look into. Obviously look
once you sell something it's out of your
hands. You never know how it's going to
be used. So we're going to have to be
very careful about that. But as long as
we are careful about what we sell and
how it is going to be used and so on,
I'm sure we can make it the defense
framework also very strong and mutually
beneficial and win-win kind of thing. So
we'll have to see about that. But the
FDA is just fantastic overall.
Rushup Tare says CCP Chinese Communist
Party purged Yang Jang Yusa, a top
general, the top general in China. Is it
true that Jang Yusia sold nuclear
secrets to the US? Was it because
Xiinping feared a coup come to other
things? The demographics are collapsing
and the economy is not growing as
earlier with only rising tech plus AI
and a huge trade surplus saving them.
China will China become a one pony trick
of exports is in such a situation can
can they do something against India,
Russia or Taiwan? Please tell your
overall assessment. Okay.
So yes, the CCP has indeed purged Jang
Yua and another general. In the past two
years or so, they've purged more than 13
top ranking generals
and accused them of various things such
as creating chaos and being in
disciplined and and whatnot. You know,
essentially nasty stuff in Chinese
Communist Party taglons.
Now um if you look at the official
uh reports coming out of Beijing, the
official Chinese Communist Party
communicates about this event about the
ouster of Jang Yushia. They don't
mention anything about selling nuclear
cigarettes or whatever. I haven't seen
any of that. I'm saying what I have seen
is that he um trampled upon party
discipline and trampled upon something
else and so on and greatly harmed you
know Chinese Communist Party interests
and national interests and military
interest and that sort of thing. Long
long wall of text with all those things
which typically are code for something
else but there's no mention of uh
selling nuclear secrets. So the Wall
Street Journal claimed that uh he was he
has been accused of selling nuclear
secrets to the US. But there's no uh
such claim or statement in the official
communications from the Chinese
Communist Party. So what is the Wall
Street Journ journal inventing news out
of thin air? What are they doing? On
what basis do they make these claims?
They have sources. What sources?
Yeah. You think you have sources in the
Chinese Communist Party who will tell
you these secrets? Really?
The western media, it it often
manufactures this fake news, blatant
fake news, right? I mean, the claim that
uh 30,000 people have been killed by the
Iranian government in Iran. What's I
mean, I'm not saying people haven't been
killed, but how do they know it's
30,000? Earlier, it was a couple of
weeks ago, it was 12,000. On what basis
do they do they create the do they they
make these claims?
I I see no factual basis to the claims
they make. It's just propaganda.
The western media is a propaganda arm of
the US and NATO. That's what it is. U
there's also been this claim that there
was a shootout in a Beijing hotel where
Mr. Xujin Ping was staying. Apparently
Mr. Xinping changes hotels every 2 three
days because he's worried about there
being a coup. That's what this story
claimed. And then uh the this Chinese
journal general Jang Yushia apparently
was about to launch a coup. And uh
Xiinping came to know about the coup
just two three hours before it happened
and he quickly left the hotel and then
Jangu Jang Yusha and his men they came
they come in and they find Xinping's
bodyguards there there's a shootout and
then eventually Jang Yusha is is is is
arrested that sort of thing that's
another story that's been making the
rounds in social media or wherever it
is. I mean on what basis do they make
these claims? Nonsense. All I can rely
on and all you should rely on is the
official communications. Of course, you
can pay attention to the little rumors
flying around. Sometimes there may be
some kernel of truth in there, but
overall, you know, don't rely on you you
can look at the rumors and so on, but
don't start believing rumors which lack
any substantiation.
Now coming to the other stuff, the
demographics are collapsing. Okay,
that's fine. But it's going to take 20
30 years for that the effect to be
really visible.
The economy is not growing as earlier.
True. The economy, the GDP seems to be
stuck wherever it is the last past three
or so years. That's weird, right? Rising
tech and AI, huge trade surplus saves
China. It's it's a good thing for China.
So, uh, in this situation, overall doom
and gloom situation.
Can China do something against India,
Russia or Taiwan? Taiwan, they can't
take. China is very, very, very scared
of a military confrontation with the US.
They know they can't win it. Now at
least some of you should be able to
understand how powerful the US is after
the developments of the past few weeks.
Right? The Chinese can't do a thing. The
US is just too powerful. The US is too
powerful. Even in China's own backyard,
Taiwan, China can't do a thing. If they
try to take Taiwan, not only will they
fail, if even if they succeed, they will
take an island that's in ruins. Nothing
of value in there. But if they go to war
over Taiwan, they're going to lose a lot
of their infrastructure. they're going
to take a lot of damage because the
Americans will will press into action
the Japanese military and the South
Korean military as well. Okay. So, it's
it's it's going to be a disaster for
China if they try to take Taiwan. Can
they do something against Russia? They
depend on Russia increasingly for oil.
The Americans control so many of the
sources of Chinese oil. The Americans,
well, they can tell the Saudis to shut
down exports of oil to China. the Saudis
will have to do it. The UAE will will
also do it if the Americans request them
to do so.
What about nations like Nigeria and
whatever Indonesia etc. They will also
do what the Americans tell them to do.
What about Iran? Well, Iran Iran may
also be pressurized into a deal with the
with the US. It is we will not bomb you
to the storage if you stop exporting oil
to China. Then Iran may also take a deal
like that. Then what does China do? It
has to depend on Russia only then.
Right? So China can't do a thing against
Russia. What about India? I mean when
China is under increasing pressure
China is under increasing pressure is
getting isolated.
Do you think it makes sense for China to
go and do some some some stupid action
against India? Makes no sense. it
actually makes sense for for China to
improve its relations with India. So
that is the overall assessment. Right
now China is under tremendous pressure
and multiple constraints of various
kinds. Right now China just wants to
weather the storm if it can. That's
where we are.
Sam Pmanik says, "Day by day, it is
getting very clear that China is afraid
of any military confrontation,
especially with the United States.
Despite growing the economy and the
military for decades, China is not able
to take Taiwan, which sits in China's
own backyard. What are the constraints
that China faces despite growing itself
so big? And why is China afraid of any
military confrontation?"
Okay, what are the constraints that
China faces?
One constraint that that China faces is
that it has almost zero power projection
capabilities. It has almost zero
offshore or extr territorial military
bases or naval bases. The Americans have
more than 800
extr territorial military bases that
essentially span the entire world. They
can intervene anywhere militarily in on
the globe at about let's say 60 minutes
notice. How many extr territorial bases
does China have? It has Djibouti which
there's a US base also on Djibouti. So
that kind of balances things out. And
there is one or two on Madagascar small.
There is Guadada which well now it's
under Pakistan is a US facile now. So
China can't do a lot in Guadada anymore
and that's about it. What else does it
have? Nothing really.
So China can't project power. The
Americans can project power all the way
into China.
They have Guam, they have the Garcia,
they have so many, they've got Japan,
they have South Korea, they have so many
other relationships. They have great
relations with the Philippines. Chinese
have been bullying the Philippines. The
Chinese are digging a hole of their own,
you know, they're in a hole of their own
making essentially. So there is the lack
of power projection capabilities that
the Chinese face. The second thing is
that the second constraint is that they
have cultivated hostile relations with
all their n neighbors.
They nearly went to war with Russia in
1969. The Russians have never trusted
China for that.
Um they have the Chinese have been
claiming territory from all their
neighbors. Nobody likes them. Nobody
trusts them. Everybody fears them. The
Chinese have deliberately
refused to demarcate the India Tibet
border for decades.
Maybe now slowly India starts getting
the advantage because we have an
undemarceted border.
All this time it's been China, China,
China with the advantage front foot.
China slowly goes on the back foot. Now
you see so the hostile relations with
all its neighbors, all of its neighbors.
Not one good relationship apart from
North Korea which is it its own story.
Then another constraint is that China is
not a net exporter
of energy. It's a net importer of
energy. China may uh
import I mean China produces about 60 to
70% of its own energy. But when it comes
to oil and gas it has to import that. So
China depends on other nations for its
critical vital energy supplies. It's
been building up strategic reserves and
all that but you know that's a stop gap
measure. China doesn't have its own oil
and gas res reserves that can you know
uh take care of its of its demand. So it
depends on nations like Iran, like Saudi
Arabia, like the UAE, like um Nigeria,
like Indonesia, like Venezuela, etc. And
all of these nations, most of them are
on excellent terms with the US
or even if they may not possibly be on
excellent terms with the US, they can't
deny US let's say requests to let's say
stop hypothetically selling oil to
China. If this US request comes in,
these nations have to agree to it. So
that's a big constraint that China
faces, right? So there's a bunch of
constraints such as these
that the Chinese face. Then then you
have the fact that the Chinese navy is
is hemmed in by three island chains.
Which are these island chains? Well,
let's crack out the map. We haven't
opened the map and thus far. Let's open
it. What are the there are three island
chains that that uh encircle China.
So the first the first island chain is
essentially you know Japan.
The Japanese islands come all the way
here. Okay. By the way, Yunauni Island
is is right next to Taiwan. So all these
islands, it's an island chain. You see
here, these are Japanese islands. Okay.
Okinawa,
Okinawa, so Okinawa is there. And then
all the other islands all the way to
Taiwan. And from Taiwan, we have the
Philippines and all the other islands,
these island nations and all. So that's
one island chain that hemps or ring
fences China and Japan is well under US
occupation. China, Taiwan is a US ally.
When it comes to nations like the
Philippines, they are bullied by China.
So they are also on excellent terms with
the US. Uh Malaysia, Singapore,
um Indonesia, all these nations that
depend on on the US for protection
against China. Vietnam also has good
relations with the US. So the Chinese
Navy is hemmed in by the first island
chain. Then you have a second island
chain and a third island chain which is
which are you know further rings of
islands. And then you have Guam here
which is a major US military base. You
will see two airports on Guam. One's
going to I know three three airports at
least three. Yeah. One of these is a I
don't know is there a domestic I mean is
there an actual international airport
here or is it all military military
bases so you have military bases here
you have naval bases and so on and it's
a major place from which the US project
power against China so you have three
island chains that ring fence China and
the Chinese ships whenever they want to
pass out into the Pacific Ocean they
have to go through rings
of US allied nations and their assets
and essentially they can't do a thing
without the Americans observing exactly
what they're doing. So that's another
constraint the Chinese face. So all
these constraints come together and of
course uh they've been trying to catch
up economically which they have done a
great job of with US help. Yeah. And
they've been trying to catch up
technologically and they've done a
fantastic job of catching up
technologically. Primarily the primary
driving factor was the Chinese
rejuvenation and reformation of its
education system. They poured in
trillions of dollars into their
education system and have made it
world-class now. Some of the best
universities in the world. Our Chinese
universities, they're all focused on
research and development and and
technology. That's why China is pretty
powerful as a technological
technologically powerful nation. Um, you
know, but they're still behind the US in
in AI. They're significantly behind the
US in in space and so on. So, these are
the constraints that China faces. Some
of the constraints
real painter says why is it that China
why is China not interested or not
investing in its power projection
capabilities I mean China's national
interest is to become a global power and
eventually beat the US but to become
even a regional power you need power
projection capabilities but it seems
China is not interested or is it part of
a big plan or a fatal mistake so real
painter rightfully says that it is in
China's national interest to become a
global power and eventually beat the US.
Well, the truth is it applies to all
nations. It is also in Bangladesh's
national interest to become a global
power and beat the US.
Yeah, it's in Bangladesh's national
interest. But can Bangladesh do that?
No, Bangladesh can't. They can't even
dream of it, right? It's not their
fault. they simply don't have the
capabilities.
So why is Bangladesh not interested or
investing in power possession
capabilities
because they they don't have the
resources to do that. They have too many
constraints.
Let's say Bangladesh wants wants to
build 10 military bases outside of
Bangladeshi territory. Who will give
them the territory to build mazes?
Will India give them land to build a
military base? India won't give it. Will
uh Sri Lanka give them some land to
Bangladesh on Sri Lankan territory to
build a Bangladeshi naval base? No. Sri
Lanka won't give it. Will Myanmar give
that to Bangladesh? No. Nobody is
willing to give anything to Bangladesh.
Right? So how does Bangladesh even if it
wants to how even if it wants to invest
in power projection, how does it do it?
It can't force anybody to do it. it
doesn't have enough money to interest
people to give up some land to and and
nobody
considers Bangladeshi you know thinks
that having Bangladeshi
military bases on their territory is a
good idea and what do you get nothing
now when it comes to China okay you
understand why Bangladesh can't do it
now let's ask China let's let's talk
about China let's say China wants to
build 10 naval bases outside of its
territory who will give China the
territory or or some land. If China, if
Indonesia gives some land to China on
Indonesian territory to build a naval
base, who does it serve? It serves
China. It's it's dangerous for
Indonesia. So why will Indonesia do
that? Why will Malaysia do that? Why
will the Philippines do that when China
already claims claims Filipino
territory? Why will Philippines do that?
Will Japan do it? No. Will South Korea
do it? No. Will India do it? Haha.
Nobody will do it. Pakistan gave some
access to China to to Guada. Let's see
how long that lasts now. Now that China
Now that Pakistan is sitting in the US
lap,
China has Djibouti some part of
Djibouti, you know, Djibouti. Uh let's
see. Djibouti. Um Djibouti is right
here. Okay. Uh Djibouti Chinese Naval
Base.
Djibouti Chinese
base. Zoom in. Here we go.
Okay. So, um here we have it,
the Chinese base. It's not telling us
exactly which one it is.
Um
yeah, once again, I'll not go and zoom
in and and try and figure out which is
Chinese, which is whichever. But the
Chinese have some access to this
Djibouti port, but so does does the US.
I mean, see, look here. This is
Djibouti, right? Let's see. We have some
interesting We have an interesting air
base here. Let's try and see what what
exactly do we have here. This looks like
radars and whatnot. Um but what kind of
aircraft do we see on this air base? Do
we see any aircraft? Look at that. Is
that a Reaper drone? American drone. So
this is a US air base. Clearly they are
using it for drones. or those nasty
Reaper or whatever drones.
So if the Chinese have some facilities
here, they are right under the nose of
the US. So once again, the Chinese can
do a lot with this
uh and so on. So the thing is nobody
wants to give China access to their
territory.
So even if China wants to do it, even if
China is willing to give a lot of money,
nations are afraid of China. Afraid of
China. they don't want to do it. So it's
not like China is not interested or
China is not investing. It's that there
is a tremendous lack of trust when it
comes to China. Nobody trusts China.
Okay? If India asks for a naval base to
in Indonesia for example or Vietnam,
they don't fear India. They know that
India is not going to turn up next
tomorrow morning with 20 ships to take
over the country.
For Ind Indonesia, it happened a
thousand years ago which was a different
story. But nobody's afraid of that,
right? India is not going to behave that
way. These nations know India doesn't do
that. That's why if India requests
Indonesia or the or Vietnam or or
Thailand or whoever Cambodia, Cambodia,
not Cambodia, but if we ask these
nations for for some kind of
relationship where we can have a naval
base or whatever, they will consider it
seriously. But China, no question of it.
So it's not like China is not
interested. They are interested. It's
not like China is not investing. They
will invest. If somebody says yes, but
nobody will say yes. Everyone is scared
of China because China has cultivated
this image through their own misdeeds
and actions of a bully of a dangerous
hgemonic nation that does not wish
well to anyone.
That's the problem for China.
Biswas says, "Can we seriously consider
the possibility of a Venezuela style
targeted attack on Kami given the
massive US naval buildup and carrier
strike groups heading towards Iran?"
Right? So, the Americans are building
up. They're creating this massive naval
buildup in
the western Indian Ocean near the
near the Persian Gulf. Let's let's take
a look at the map. What exactly are we
seeing? Give me a second. Let me um
Okay, so we are seeing a US naval
buildup. There are aircraft carrier
strikes strike groups that are loitering
in the western Indian Ocean. This region
here, the region that's called the
so-called Arabian Sea, the western
Indian Ocean region near the Gulf of
Oman possibly not far away. maybe uh you
know western India, southern Pakistan
that region possibly
the the Americans also have
you know military bases in u
the west Asia region whether it is uh
Saudi Arabia, whether it is um Qatar,
whether it is the UAE,
even Iraq
um and these nations. So Iran is
essentially um encircled.
Pakistan is now a US asset. The
Americans can use Pakistani airspace for
whatever they want. Pakistan wants no.
Uh Afghanistan also is well for whatever
reason on America's payroll right now.
So Iran is kind of you know encircled
and the the Americans have sent these
aircraft carrier strike groups uh in the
region proximate to Iran. So the
Americans are building up the building
up a milit they are creating a military
buildup that can be used
to let's say either invade Iran or
possibly launch strikes at Iran. Now
what's the point of launching a strike
on Iran?
What's the objective? The there has to
be a clear objective. Um Trump has
claimed that he has taken out Iran's um
military uh sorry nuclear program.
Um so then if it is if that is taken
care of then why would you do a strike
on Iran? uh you can't just effect a
regime change by doing a few uh air
strikes on a country a country of Iran
size with an entrenched uh government.
So then if you do an air strike or or a
targeted strike it could possibly be a
decapitation strike
which would target the top leadership of
the Iranian government possibly
possibly. Yeah, that's that's obviously
all speculation here, but it is
certainly a theoretical possibility.
So they so what does the US see we have
to first understand what does the US
really want when it comes to Iran? Are
they interested in freedom and human
rights and democracy? They couldn't care
less. The Americans could couldn't care
less about freedom and human rights and
democracy. All they are interested in is
Iran's oil, its energy resources. That's
what the Americans want to control.
So they may, you know, do back channel
negotiations with the Iran government
that we will not do a regime change,
but in exchange for us not doing a
regime change, you guys need to
sell all your oil to us or let us
control the oil. all the oil you sell it
to the US and the US will decide what
happens to the oil. Don't sell it to
China. Don't sell it to anybody else.
Sell it to us or sell it to nations that
we approve. That is actually the US will
be happy with the third of a deal.
Uh they may also demand that Iran stop
supplying Russia with various military
components and all. Iran may or may not
agree to it. And let's say the Americans
make these demands primarily about oil
and energy and Iran says no. Then what
could the US do? They could do a
decapitation strike on on Thran and take
out Mr. Kabi. It's very difficult for
the Americans to go and abduct Kobeni
the way they did with Mr. Maduro in
Karakas. But they may do a decapitation
strike
if there is collateral damage. Human
beings. Well, who cares? It's Iranians,
right? Brown people, not white. Uh so
that could happen. that could happen and
then you after after taking out how many
whoever is left of the Iranian
leadership they could once again repeat
those demands okay now let me ask you
again will you agree to what I'm saying
or do you need more punishment so that's
something the Americans could do right
so obviously the Iranian government will
be aware of this that the Americans can
carry out such actions and they will
obviously take uh take uh measures to
ensure that the top leadership isn't
taken on by the Americans it could a
game of cat and mouse, right? That sort
of thing. Uh and if the Americans do
strike at Thran and fail to take out the
leadership or top leadership, the
Iranians won't sit back and just wait.
They will launch counter strikes at
various American assets in the region.
So u that could lead to a long drawn out
conflict, an increasingly escalating
conflict that could be disastrous for
the entire region, right? Uh so whatever
the Americans do, whatever actions they
take will have to be really well
calculated.
But yes, we can certainly seriously
consider the possibility of a targeted
attack on the on the Iranian
government's top leadership. We can
certainly consider the possibility of
that happening. The Americans are are
putting together a major military
buildup and naval buildup in the region
which obviously um you know indicates
that they are considering uh the
possibility of taking such actions.
Um and yeah it it all all depend on how
how much pressure Trump is under uh
whether
whether Israel is able to successfully
pressurize Trump into doing this whether
other nations in the region like Saudi
Arabia, Oman um UEIE etc are able to
tell Trump not to do this because it
could hurt those these nations as well.
It depends on multiple factors. At the
end of the day it depends on what's
Trump. If Trump decides it has to
happen, it may happen and then once a
chain of events is set off, you never
know what direction it goes in. So you
can only control whether you start the
process or don't start the process. Once
the process starts, you never know
what's going to what's going to happen,
what direction it takes. So yes, I think
uh the possibility does exist that
America may do a targeted attack on the
Iranian government's top leadership,
including Mr. Kabani. It's possible.
It's certainly possible.
Rushab says, "What is happening with
Canada? Reports say that Trump allegedly
met separatists who want to separate
Alberta from Canada. Quebec is known,
but how come Alberta has come into the
picture?" Mark Carney called out the
rules-based order in Davos. He went to
China and signed a trade deal with
Xiinping. Trump said 100% tariffs and it
ended. Why is the US doing this to
Canada which can't survive without the
US and is this the reason of uptrend in
India Canada ties and a potential
uranium deal and trade deal? So
when it comes to Canada and separatism
what Indians think of is this
Kalistthani nonsense that the Canadians
have been have been cultivating for
decades. The Canadian government has
been cultivating
and and and promoting Kalistthani
terrorists and separatists on their
territory for decades. A lot of these
Kalistani separatists are Canadian
citizens. Some of them are outright
terrorists,
anti-India terrorists. They don't do
terrorism against Canadian citizens or
or citizens of any other nation. Only
against India.
They blew up a 747, a Boeing 747, the
Kesan. Which year was it? 1986 and this
killed a large number of Canadian
citizens but those Canadian citizens
were brown Indian origin so it didn't
doesn't matter right so Canada for the
longest time has been harboring and
encouraging
and protecting Kalistthani terrorists
and separatists on its soil right now
see see the irony
today Trump wants to separate Alberta
from Canada the Canadians have been
protecting
separatists who want to break India Khal
the so-called Kalistthan out of India
right today Canada is facing the very
real prospect of getting bulcanized by
Trump so what's his deal with Alberta
right I mean we obviously those of you
who are who have some understanding of
Canada will know that you know when it
comes to separatism in Canada it's
typically Quebec Quebec is a
French-speaking territory is the capital
Montreal right and the rest of Canada is
English speaking then it's this uneasy
union of this French speakaking
territory then this English speaking
territory very different histories right
France and England not not the best of
friends at the best of times uh so
Quebec has uh seen multiple calls for
independence there have been referendums
that have been narrowly defeated
referendums for independence
uh so when we think of Canada and and
separatism we think of Quebec what about
Alberta so let's go Go to the map. What?
First of all, what is Alberta? Let's
see. Okay. Um, Alberta, Canada.
Alberta, Canada. What part of Canada is
this? This part of Canada is Alberta.
Pretty big part of Canada. And two of
the big cities, major cities in Canada,
Edmonton and Calgary, are in Alberta.
So, um, and then you have
the western region, which is British
Columbia. But what is special about
Alberta is that it has it it is
home to the majority of Canada's oil
reserves.
Canada is an oil rich nation and a
majority of these reserves oil reserves
are in Alberta. And now most of these
most of this oil goes into the into the
US. It's sold to the US.
So uh now Trump says that you know
because Canada is showing signs of
dissatisfaction with the US and it is
not happy with American bullying. It is
not bending low enough for the US and
for Trump's pleasure and so on. So Trump
seems to be threatening Canada with
bulcanization.
Earlier he had been saying that he will
make Canada the 51st state of the US and
if the US so desires they can do it.
Canada has no defense against the US.
Canada depends on the US for so many
things. If the Americans want to take
Canada and make it their 51st state, all
they have to do is walk in and take
over. There'll be almost no resistance.
They won't even need an army to do that.
They'll just need cops perhaps. Just
walk in and take over. That's it.
And uh Trump has been
well when Justin Trudeau was still the
prime minister he used to call Trump
used to call Trudeau the governor of the
state of Canada right that sort of
thing. So Trump has been making these
these remarks for quite some time and
now he apparently he or some of his
minions held a meeting with Albertan
separatists.
So
you see we in India
we are aware of American attempts to
bulcanize India from time to time from
the uh 20th century onwards.
I mean the Americans funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism against India. We
know that uh some of this financing and
funding went into the Kalistthan
movement, the 1980s, the Punjab
insurgency and terrorism which uh which
we had to fight and bring to a hard
fought end right the Americans funded
and finance that
um the Kashmir issue that again
the whatever actions Pakistan has taken
the terrorist actions and all that you
know terrorism in Kashmir for decades
spilling out of Pakistan all funded and
financed by the US. Right? Right now we
are facing a major major crisis in
Manipur. Right now the news media is not
reporting it but Manipur is under
foreign occupation. At least half of
Manipur is under foreign occupation by
cookie infiltrators who have walked in
from Burma. And the objective is to
create this artificial fake nation
called Cookie Land for Christ. Cookie
Land for Christ. Who is behind this?
It's one once again the US. When the
Bangladeshes claim that they will make
India's seven sister states in the far
easting states part of Bangladesh,
who is encouraging them to do this? It's
the US. So all of this bulcanization
these all these bulcanization projects
about versus India. The Americans also
play this game of subnational diplomacy
in India.
Once again that the objective is to
balconize India. So we in India, India,
some of us are aware of the American
efforts and attempts to play this game
of bul bulcanizing India. But Trump,
he's going to do it even to his own
allies. He wants to balkcanize Canada
now. He wants to take Greenland and
balconize Denmark.
So um yeah, that's that's the US. The US
has no friends. The US has no allies.
The US only has disposable assets who
must be useful or they will be
reconfigured until they are useful.
Right? The US is an empire. An empire
has no friends. So that's what the US
is. I think it's very clear now that
this is the game the US plays.
Um now what about the India Canada
relationship? Well, Karan wanted a deal
with China did not quite happen, right?
If Canada wants a deal with India, will
the I mean even if you side it, will the
Americans allow Canada to operationalize
it? Uranium,
uranium is a pretty it's not oil, right?
Uranium has other uses too.
Um, of course, India will be happy to
buy Canadian uranium, Canadian oil,
Canadian whatever. India is the world's
largest nation in terms of population.
India wants everything. India wants to
buy everything from whoever has
something to offer. So, we'll be h happy
to um have a trade deal with Canada, FT
of some kind. We'll be happy to have a
uranium deal also with Canada. Will the
Americans allow Canada to do this? The
Canadians, especially and the the Carney
government, they are clear that it's
beneficial for Canada to have better
relations with India, perhaps mend
fences with India. But will the
Americans allow them to do this? That's
the big question. I think uh well I'll
be actually surprised if this happens
this this set of deals with Canada
and even if it happens will it actually
go ahead will it be ratified even if
it's ratified will will we still say the
operation operationalization of the deal
for example we have this deal with the
United States
for the sale for the sale
of fighter jet engines to India what
F414 engines of whichever it
We have signed the deal. We have paid
the money. The Americans aren't really
delivering the jet engines and that's
why the program is frozen right now.
So even if you sign a deal, everything
is operationalized
and so on between India and Canada, the
Americans could still step in the way
and stop things from proceeding. the
Americans have hard power
and they can't the Canadians can't
prevent the Americans from from uh you
know disrupting a deal. So that's why I
think uh we can go ahead with the deal
with Canada and so on but the Americans
may come in the way and disrupt it.
That's a strong possibility in my
opinion.
Arya Vashisha says, "Despite being
despite Russia being so powerful, how
did the US develop so much influence in
Russia's neighborhood, the Central Asian
nations and in the Caucasus region? Did
the US do this through military might or
economic power or something else?"
Okay, so first of all, let's go to the
map and talk and take a look at what
nations we are talking about. Give me a
second. Okay. Uh where is map? Map is
here. Okay. So let's uh talk about
Russia. Russia. So what are the nations
we're talking about? After the break up
of the USSR, you had all these central
Asian republics that became independent.
Kazakhstan, Usbekiststan, Turkmanistan,
Azarbaijan, Tajakistan, Kyistan. We also
have Armenia that became independent and
Georgia. This is the Caucasus region
we're talking about. And obviously we
have the the uh uh Ukraine became
independent, Belerus, Latvia, Lithuania,
Estonia and so much more, right? I mean
that's about it. Not really so much more
but that's about it. So now the thing is
the US has developed a significant
amount of influence in this region
whether it is the caucases region
whether it is uh the stans
Kazakhstanistan Turkmanistan
uh Kyrgystan and so on let me give you
an example for okay let's go to the
capital of Kyrgystan bishkek for first
of all Kygystan is essentially literally
a stones throw away from India
literally
I mean, see what's the distance from,
let's say, Mumbai to Lei? What's the
distance? It's about 1,700 km, right?
What's the distance between Lei and the
capital of Kiran, Bishk?
It's about 1,000 km. You see, it's it's
much closer. Um, and and the border,
it's it's even closer between India and
Kystan. So let's go to the capital of
Kistan, Bishkek.
Okay. And uh let's see. A UA B I S H K E
K. What is AUA Bishkek? What is it?
There we have it. AUCA. What is the
AUCA?
Um where is it? Okay, let us see what
AUCA is. Um,
it's the American University of Central
Asia. So,
the Americans more than 20 years ago set
up an American University of Central
Asia in the capital of Kyrgyzstan,
Bishk. And that's just one example of
the American penetration in the region.
So, the question is how did the
Americans
uh, you know, how how did they succeed
in penetrating Central Asia? to this
extent when Russia is so powerful and so
on that's the argument or that's the
question
right the thing is this how powerful was
Russia in the year 2000 first of all
let's see when was AUCA founded okay
established
uh when
AA bishke
um American university do you have okay
Wikipedia
does it say when it was founded
established in 1993
the USSR broke up in what 199 1999 91
couple of years later the Americans have
established
an American university of central Asian
Bishek the Americans move fast past fast
so in 1993 the USSR had been dissolved
and Russia was in a shambles
Russia its economy was on its knees.
Russia was beset by problems. They had a
drunken president in power, Boris Yelen.
When did Putin come to power? Late
1990s,
right? 98 or 97, whichever year it was,
that's when Putin comes to power. And he
first comes into office. He only later
gets power. He slowly is able to acquire
power slowly slowly. and he slowly drags
Russia back from the brink. In 2005,
Russia was still not regarded as a major
power.
Around 2010, that's when the West
started, you know, getting wary of
Russia once again because Putin had
spent a decade remodernizing the Russian
military. So until 2010, Russia was not
really really powerful
and it's it's its uh influence in
Central Asia and it's it's the the fact
that it regards Central Asia as its
exclusive sphere of influence. It was
like India's claim that the Indian Ocean
is our strategic backyard. It's a
slogan. It's not operational in reality.
H
Yeah. Right. So that's why Russia is
very powerful today. But look at how
Russia was in 2000. In 2005, in 1995, it
was nowhere compared to what it is
today. And that's why the Americans were
able to penetrate these Central Asian
nations deeply. And that's what the
Russians are trying to undo right now.
Yeah.
real painter says how can we assume that
India after hitting a reasonable GDP or
military growth in the next 5 to 8 years
won't become an American vasal or
whatever kind of vasal because we still
will be having the same inferior system
that we have today and maybe
possibly hypothetically a compromised
leader may come to power after the 5 to
8 year mark how are we going to deal
with it. What's the guarantee we will
not become a vasal of somebody?
There's no guarantee. There's no
guarantee whatsoever that we will not
become a vasal.
So how do you guarantee you don't become
a vasal? First of all, you need to have
hard power which is you know GDP growth
and military growth. Military power also
should grow and obviously you need
internal cohesion which means you need
infrastructure and so on. All of that
stuff and you need a robust economy. You
need robust manufacturing technology all
of that right so India we are our
economy is growing sure we have a
massive population we have massive
massive land mass big resources and all
that's why it's natural that our economy
will grow
and our military spending expenditure is
growing proportionally to our economic
growth
right so let's say in 5 to 8 years we
are 7 trillion economy or whatever it is
$8 trillion economy Fantastic.
But the but we have internal problems.
Our system is rotten. It's a colonial
system.
Our institutions are colonial in nature.
We have a governance system, an
electoral system that is unnatural for
us. Westminster style parliamentary
democracy.
a system that evolved over a few
centuries on a small island in the
Atlantic and it has now been forced upon
a subcontinent-sized
nation. simply unsuitable for us. And we
have all these structural issues and
whatnot. Things that compromise us, the
alleged corruption all over the place,
allegedly
so many issues, a totally rotten
education system that ensures that
people don't know how to, you know, what
is right from what's wrong. people
people still divided increasingly on
cast lines,
reservations, freebies, unconditional
freebies,
not conditional freebies, unconditional
freebies, all the problems,
all these problems together, they they
can create the perfect storm. You throw
some money, some cash at somebody,
they'll vote for you. You throw some
alcohol at somebody, they'll vote for
you. That's that's the kind of people we
have in India. The quality of your
population depends on the quality of the
education system. And the Indian
education system is trash. It is rotten.
And no attempt has been made to to to
reform it. Nothing. The new education
policy 2020, it's a joke. It's not
reform. It's just cosmetic makeover.
That's it.
So
considering the fact that no no
significant reforms have even been
attempted in the past 12 13 years to
clean up the system.
Considering that there is no guarantee
that even after becoming a larger
economy and so on there's no guarantee
that we will not be vilized. All it
takes is one electoral result
in a in a general election to have a
complete U-turn in the story of India.
The government had 12 13 years to reform
everything to clean up the system.
So yeah, there is no guarantee. It's
it's possible in 5 years we could be
somebody's vasal and that will send us
back by 200 years another 200 years of
slavery. It's possible.
Yeah.
Amisha says Kiran Riiju says Arunachal
could become the Qatar of India. Is this
a crazy take or do we have real
potential for this? So um I'm not really
sure what Mr. Riu meant by Qatar of
India but let's think about so I'm not
sure what exactly was the meaning but
let's take a look quickly at Arunachal
Pradesh and what
potential it has so first of all those
of you who may not be aware there are
people in India who still don't know
where Manipur Arunachal these states are
many people still don't know this no so
Arunachal Pradesh is the north it's the
far easternmost
state of India in the far east the
northernmost state um it has it has a
border with essentially Tibet right
Tibet um northern border with Tibet it's
a massive massive state okay uh let's
see Arunachala Pradesh
I just want to see the boundaries of the
state
um why is it not showing the boundaries
of the state if I say let's say um West
Bengal
Will it show me the boundaries of the
state? It does show me the boundaries of
the state of West Bengal. Google Maps
does. Okay. Let's say I say Assam.
Assam. Will it show me the boundaries of
Assam?
Not quite. Okay. Let's say Bihar.
Bihar. Well, it does show me the
boundaries of Bihar. So when it comes to
the states in India's far east, Google
maps does not show the boundaries for
some reason. Okay, let's say Manipur,
Manipur, does it show the boundaries of
Manipur? It shows the boundaries of
Manipur. So when you have a state that
has a border with Chinese occupied
territory,
does Assam have that?
I'm not sure. What about Nagaland?
What about Nagaland?
It shows the borders of Nagaland because
there is no common boundary with Chinese
occupied territory. So it shows that
what about Migallaya?
Migallaya
it does show this. Now what about
Arunachal Pradesh?
It won't show me the boundaries. So
Google is taking China's side in this
matter. Let's see if I place my pointer
um in Chinese occupied territory. What
what do I get? Okay, here it says
Ningchi, Tibet, China. Okay, if I put it
down here below the border, south of the
border, Indian territory, it says Tibet
China. In Indian territory, look at
that. Would you believe it? Indian
territory it says Tibet China. This is
the game Google is playing. The United
States is considers China to be a rival,
but Google supports Chinese claims on
Indian territory.
Okay, look at this. Let's see what it
says here. It says Tibet, China. In
Indian territory.
This is really interesting. Here, Tibet,
China. In Indian territory. What about
here? Unavailable. But closer to the
borders, it will say Tibet China. Okay,
here is Indian territory. Here it says
Tibet, China.
What about here? Unavailable.
Would you believe it? So this is what
Google does. This is what Google does.
It shows Indian territory as Chinese
territory. Now coming back to Amisha's
question. Uh so so okay, Arunachal
Pradesh is this big large state that we
have in the northernmost part of India's
far east. Uh now the question is um
what are the resources that we have in
Arunachal Pradesh uh that could make it
make the state u valuable. So we have u
massive forests first of all in
Arunachal Pradesh we probably have a lot
of natural mineral resources which would
require mining for extraction but we
have that in Arunachal Pradesh we have
these massive rivers
uh which could give us which would
generate hydro power if we set up these
hydroelect electric projects in the
state over these rivers. Of course we
would have to do it judiciously. We
don't want to uh put dams all over the
place which could be harmful to the
environment and create all kinds of
potentially seismic or tectonic issues.
We we don't want that. Um so we have
mineral resources,
we have forests, we don't want to bring
the bring the forest down for forward.
We don't want to do that. We have
mineral resources and we have a lot of
water and a lot of hydroele electricity
potential in the state. Okay. Now the
state
okay let's let's let's just do this
Google search Arunachal Pradesh
land area
Pradesh Pradesh land area what's the
land area 83743
square kilm okay 83,000 km
population
okay 1.58 million population density
uh the lowest population density among
all of Indian states 17 inhabitants per
square kilometer that's the 2011 census
badly outdated whatever it's still the
last census we have 17 inhabitants per
square kilometer
so if we want to develop let's say we
want to do some mining mining activities
let's say we want to construct
hydroelect electric projects ac or
rivers or whatever we will need labor
for that.
The population of Arunachal Pradesh
probably cannot provide all the labor
that's needed for this. So we have to
bring in labor forces from other states.
If we do that it could work but
politically it could be a problem. It
could be problematic. We have this
Christian conversion mafia that is
operational in Pradesh.
Right.
I I hear that Pradesh is being rapidly
converted to Christianity. So if you
bring in migrant workers from other
states to do this work, the local local
Christian conversion mafia could create
political issues. That's one issue.
That's one possibility.
Um there could be if we if we discover
mineral
riches resources and we start mining if
we propose mining there could be uh
protests from environmental activists
and NOS's and all. So I would say look
the potential is there but India in in
India politically everything is can be
can can be a minefield. There are all
these vested interest groups at play and
all the groups many of these groups have
ties to foreign actors, foreign powers
and the objective is to stop any kind of
development from happening in India.
So the potential I'm sure is there to
become the Qatar or the or the whatever
of India. Potential is there. But do we
have the political fortitude to make
this happen?
If we do have the political fortitude to
make it happen, is is it going to happen
in the next one year, next 3 years, next
5 years, next 10 years, next 20 years?
If it takes 20 years to happen, then
what's the point? Let's make it happen
next two, three years. When the USSR
broke up, the Americans established an
American University of Central Asia and
Bishk in just two years. They make
things happen fast. In India, um, we'll
talk about things and all. I'm I'm I'm
sure that you know the potential is
there but then let's operationalize it
right let's make it happen not over the
next 20 30 50 years but now next 2 3
years 5 years
so it could become the Qatar or whatever
of India it has the potential but
we like to talk a lot in India will we
actually make it happen that's the big
question
Shanks says
India, France, China and Russia hold
large annual military parades such as
Republic Day parade, Basti Day parade,
National Day parade and Victory Day
parade. 9th of May, right? Russia
victory day parade parade. What do these
parades achieve? Are they about
demonstrating military power,
cultivating national unity or projecting
international prestige? In contrast, the
most powerful country, the United
States, does not hold such annual
military parades. Why does this
difference exist? And what does it
reveal about government priorities,
civil military relations, and the
signals conveyed domestically and
internationally?
Right? Military parades, what do they
achieve? So, we have
annual parades in India, France, China,
and Russia. And these parades, they
achieve multiple objectives. These are
like multi-purpose tools like you know
one tool achieves multiple things. It's
like a Swiss army knife. Lots of things
can be achieved simultaneously. So these
parades they simultaneously display
military power. They they cultivate
natural
national unity. They project
international prestige. Um they also are
showcases for geopolitical connections
and right and and and alliances and so
on. And all of these things for each
nation is done to different extents and
different degrees. There's a balance.
The these are the various goals of a
parade. But the the the various
components are balanced out in different
ways for each nation. It depends on the
nation, its historical narrative and the
context and so on. So one thing these
parades do is they showcase military
power. They will you can use them to
display new platforms whether it's
missiles, new kinds of missiles that we
display. Whether it is new tanks,
whether it is new aircraft. You want to
demonstrate modernization. You want to
demonstrate to your adversaries the kind
of deterrence capabilities you possess.
You want to reassure your population
that you know we have all these
fantastic weapons that will safeguard
our national interest, our territorial
territorial interest and so on. So
that's what you know military power.
That's how we would demonstrate military
power through the parades. And it's a
high visibility way of demonstrating
military power and doing strategic
signaling. You know, you don't have to
do mobilizations and deployments of your
armed forces. You can just do a parade
and you can showcase all of these things
and achieve this objective, right? Um
then obviously it's about fostering
national pride, national unity um for
nations like China, the legitimacy of
the regime, the fact that the claim that
we still have the mandate of heaven,
that sort of thing. So um for India,
it's the republic day, right? Uh January
26. So we are linking the armed forces
to the the founding founding of the
Indian Republic, right? We're linking
these two things. for France Basti day
it's about the revolution the French
revolution 1789 right you're linking the
armed forces to the revolution it's it's
conducted uh for Russia um it's Russia's
defeat of Nazi Germany that has been
commemorated commemorated and the armed
forces are are being linked to that
achievement and for China it is the the
the the power and the control that the
Chinese Communist Party has achieved
over its military um so that's that's
what I do and obviously you You do this
for international prestige. You invite
foreign leaders. You sometimes even
invite foreign contingents to march in
your parade, right? So you use the
parade as a stage for for creating
alliances or showcasing alliances or
strengthening alliances in major
partnerships, right? Uh if you if if you
have a guest from another country, you
know, a president, prime minister, you
can showcase your domestic defense
industry, you know, indigenous systems.
Whether it's India, Russia, China,
right? even in France I suppose. Uh so
you can use that to showcase your
defense industry and maybe get arms
sales to a nice export market. Yeah, you
could do that. So
So that's that's one thing you can
that's another thing you can do. Um when
it comes to nations like China, China is
an authoritarian nation, right? It uses
its parade for
telling its population that the regime
that rules you is has legitimacy. It has
the mandate of heaven and it's also used
for uh
for frightening the neighbors or for
scaring the neighbors for coercing the
neighbors coercive signaling right so
that's what the Chinese do u the Chinese
use the parade their parade as as a tool
of state craft um Mr. The Xinping is
typically there, right? He's usually
there. So, it it it is used to
demonstrate that Shriinping is the man
who controls this massive massive uh set
of military equipment and all these men
who are marching, they're all marching
and saluting Xiinping. So, Xiinping is
the legitimate leader of China, right?
And obviously these parades have been
happening for years and years and
decades. So, historical continuity. Mr.
Xiinping carries on the flame of the
torch that Maoong Mao Maoong lit right
so he that establishes Xiinping's
legitimacy and of course you demonstrate
advanced weaponry so that will reassure
the Chinese audience it will it will
deter foreign audiences um that sort of
thing right um and so on that's the kind
of thing you do so you have Russia also
which has its own tradition France also
has the basidi tradition Russia has the
9th of May tradition which which which
connects today's Russia to the Soviet
victory in 1945 over the Nazis, right?
It honors the millions of Soviet and
Russian war dead the soldiers who died
for the motherland and it also
emphasizes that we are currently combat
ready. We can deal with any situation
right and we will demonstrate our our
military might and our military hardware
on the red square that sort of thing. Um
so that's about India, Russia, China and
France. France also basti day right 1979
sorry 1789
it commemorates the revolutionary birth
of the French Republic and it it in
includes involves tributes to the heroes
of France. Um so uh France uses the
military format to to underscore
underline under underline its its civic
values and to repudiate the old
monarchical values the monarchy right
and France also has allied units who who
march on the basti day parade. Now why
does the US lack an annual parade? Why
is that? So from the time the US So how
was the US founded? The US was founded,
you know, the US fought a war of
independence against the British
occupiers who were the same people.
Yeah. Uh but but they defeated the the
British and uh
and that was the founding of the US
1776.
From that time onwards when the when the
United States was founded, American
political culture has has typically
regarded large standing armies with
threats to the republican identity of
the US. So this
because of this the US is not very
comfortable with these massive central
parades that
that have the effect of visually
elevating the military over the civilian
leaders. Okay. And the US already
signals power through global
deployments, through wars, through
regime change operations, through
alliances, through technological
demonstrations, through its aircraft
carrier strike groups, through bombers
flattening cities and those so-called
freedom of navigation operations in the
South China Sea and whatnot. So the US
demonstrates its military might in real
world scenarios routinely.
It routinely every few years there's a
reg re regime somewhere. It goes into
Karakas and plattens a few buildings and
and kidnaps Maduru and his wife and
takes them back to the US. There you
have your military might demonstrated.
You don't need a parade for that. Right?
So a domestic parade is is not really a
important as a credibility signal for
the US and that's why the US doesn't it
it dispenses with these parades. It uses
the military in real world scenarios and
showcases to its people. There we have
it. We are the most powerful nation in
the world. Done deal.
Okay.
Lego online says, "Bro, the hard power
nations are some or the other way trying
to strengthen their strangle hold over
other nations. The tech power nations
are in some way or the other other
trying to make the world dependent on
their technology and products. And why
is our bhat still stuck in this jati
this and jati that and cast cast cast?
No difference between the ruling
alliances or all the opposition
combined. But the most crucial question
mark is hanging over the UGC. It has
been trending more than any other
popular sports event for the past 24
hours. I understand you more or less try
to skip questions that are attached with
Indian politics. But how about I take
this one?
UGC
the UGC rules or whatever it was of uh
creating divisions in Indian society
based on cast and laboring labeling
certain groups within India's population
as permanently oppressed groups
and labeling certain groups within
India's population as permanent
oppressors.
What was the objective of doing this?
The Supreme Court has struck it down or
or paused it or whatever.
But what was the objective of this to
create more divisions in Indian society?
Haven't the British and the former
Turk occupiers done enough to create
divisions in Indian society?
You're creating more and more and more
permanent divisions in Indian society.
creating a permanent sense of victimhood
somewhere in a permanent sense that some
people are are permanently oppressors.
Isn't the job of the government to unify
the country to to to to
end whatever divisions and differences
exist and bring the people together
harmoniously? Isn't that the job of the
government?
But you see, we are a democracy. In
democracy, you it it really pays to
paint some people as permanent victims
and to then portray yourself as the
savior and those guys have been
oppressing you for 5,000 years or
whatever
and then reap the political benefits of
that rewards all the time.
That is cynical politics
that is
poisonous for the civilization.
I'm not sure the Indian government even
recognizes India as a civilization
anymore. We are not really a
civilization in the real sense of the
world anymore. We are a colonized
nation.
The politicians seem to be all they seem
to care about is short-term benefits to
hell with the civilization and long-term
future.
Right?
Our politicians claim that cast is a
very bad thing in in India and cast must
be annihilated.
Right? Cast is evil. Cast must be
annihilated.
I agree. Annihilate cast completely.
So what stops them from doing it?
Whatever reservations you are giving,
give the reservations on the base of on
the basis of a family's economic
situation,
financial condition, not so-called cast.
What is stopping them from doing it?
Remove
cast from all official documents,
government documents, whether it's a
birth certificate or death certificate
or school certificate or or or whatever
certificate. Remove cast completely and
permanently. End of cast unlation of
cast. Do it right and then give
reservations fairly on the basis of each
family's economic situation.
That's the end of your cast issue. But
the government will not do it. Your
politicians want to they claim that they
are against cast but they are the ones
who are keeping cast alive forever.
Who who believes in cast today?
You go to any city, go and sit in a
restaurant. Do you care what's the
so-called cast of the guy who's serving
you? Do you care what's the so-called
cast of the of the person who is the
cook, who's the chef, who's handling
your food and chopping your vegetables
and and whatever else? Do you care? When
you sit in an aircraft, when you sit in
um in a bus or in a train,
do you care what's the cast of the
person sitting next to you?
When you're traveling, when you're
walking in a crowded street and you
you're bumping shoulders with people, do
you care what's the cast of anybody?
It is these politicians who are keeping
cast alive. The British
made it mandatory for government
documents to have cast. They did this
more than 100 years ago. Today's
politicians are keeping this alive
for their own benefit, not for the
benefit of the country.
Annihilate cast. End it completely.
What's stopping you?
This is terrible. Absolutely terrible.
And it's so incredibly disappointing.
That's all I have to say about this.
I've broken my rule of not discussing
local politics of internal matters of
India, but I suppose I should in this
matter.
Nirvana Shank says the Delhi Sultanit
and Muggal Empire were foreign rulers.
Yes, foreign occupiers of India. How did
the indigenous systems of governance
persist under these foreign occupiers
and what does that say about um Indian
cultural resilience? Thank you for your
attention to this matter. See the Delhi
Sultanate and the Muggal Kingdom which
eventually became a Muggal Empire. These
were foreign rulers, foreign occupiers
of India. They were foreigners that
tried to impose foreign systems of
administration, foreign language and
foreign religion upon the Indian people.
And they were successful to a certain
extent which is why we have the
situation that we have in India today
demographically and so on and so forth.
So how did indigenous systems of
governance persist under the muggles?
Let's say the muggles.
nothing persisted under the muggles or
the Turks. The first thing they would do
is if they won a victory, they would
kill the king, behead the king, and do
nasty nasty atrocious stuff with um with
the king's whoever survived in the in in
in in the king's family in the army and
so on typically. Yeah. So, we know what
they did. We'll not discuss that here.
And then you have the population that is
subjugated right by the by the muggles
by the Turks. What happens to them? Uh
did some kind of indigenous system of
governance was that continued? Nothing.
Nothing. They brought in foreign systems
of governance. They brought in you know
administration in foreign languages.
First Chakatai Turk then eventually
Persian.
Right?
So the entire system of governance was
changed, the language was changed, the
systems were changed, the titles of the
officials were changed. U eventually the
muggles introduced the Zabindari system
which just stole land from Indians.
Everything was changed. Nothing
indigenous was allowed to survive. So
and yet Indian civilization kind of
survived somehow. How did it survive?
See the muggles and the Turks what they
did was they even destroyed all the
temples. the major temples. So the
Indian education system was destroyed,
the universities were destroyed, the
libraries were burned down.
So in what way did India's culture
demonstrate resilience? Well, people
refused to convert. People were willing
to die rather rather than convert.
After Persia fell to the Arabs, Persia
converted mostly most of the Persian
population converted to the religion of
the Arabs in 2030 years. in India didn't
work that way. India was resilient.
Um
Indian the Indian education system
survived. We lost all the great texts
and all the libraries and millions of
manuscripts and whatnot and the
professors and the big universities. But
at the lowest levels at the village in
town levels those little temples that
survived they continued the guruisha
parumpara and the old old education
system to some extent at least you know
like primary level education that
continued that's why the the the the you
know the stories that went that had to
be passed on orally those those stories
continued th those memories of the old
days continued. People still still
taught the old stories Ramayan
Mahabharat all that the Vedas all of
that all the texts were destroyed most
of the texts were destroyed but so the
the oral tradition still continued
so that is cultural resilience to some
extent the Indian education system
survived
quietly they kept it quiet you're being
ruled by foreigners they don't care
about education anyway so you quietly
keep your education system going on um
Indian women had to cover up so that
that permanent change came into Indian
culture, right? Indian women were the
freest women in the world. Now they had
to cover up and they had to they had to
become invisible. That ch that changed
and that became part of Indian culture.
Today women that's Indian culture kind
of right. Um
indigenous systems of governance did not
persist in any way, shape or form unless
you had a kingdom that was uh still
independent and still not under Turic
occupation.
In that case, some system of indigenous
governance could perhaps survive would
have survived for some time. Um, yeah.
So, it was it was that sort of thing
and India's culture was resilient.
That's why India still is a majority
indigenous religion practicing region.
Krishna of the Surin numbers Netherlands
says do you think there will ever be a
second partition of India? I'm asking
this because there's a certain religious
group in India that represents an
incredibly large massive minority. It's
not a minority. It's a second majority.
Um will there ever be a second partition
of India? No, there won't be a second
partition of India. See today we I don't
know how many Bangladeshes we have in
India.
There could be close to 100 million
possibly Bangladeshes in India. I would
say at least 50 million must be there.
I mean if there are so many of them and
there is nothing being done to deport
them. Why will they ask for a partition
of India? They'll just reproduce,
multiply and then say that we are the
majority and now India is is no longer
what it used to be. That's what they do.
India is Bangladesh part two they would
say now in a few decades.
So they don't seek a partition of India.
the infiltrators. The infiltrators and
whoever else they seek to become a
majority in India.
I don't think the aim is anymore to have
a second partition of India. Not going
to happen.
Amisha says, "Why isn't King Leopold II
who is responsible for the deaths of
about 10 million Congalles? Why isn't he
vilified on the same level as Hitler or
Stalin? Why do Belgians say the
atrocities in the Belgian Congo were
Leopold II's fault and Belgium wasn't
responsible for them? So you see King
Leopold II of Belgium. He ruled Congo.
It was called Belgian Congo from I think
1885 to 1908.
Okay, that's what 15 + 8 is 23 years.
And during those 23 years, he unleashed
the worst of depraved barbarities on the
people of the Congo. And u then after
everything is done and dusted, he
destroyed all the documents, most of the
documents about what he had done. So
today, that's why there is ambiguity
about exactly how many people he killed.
Some of the things he did was he created
these child labor camps. They would kill
off lots of congalles people that gave
rise to lots of orphans whose parents
had been murdered by the Belgians. And
those children would then be taken as
slaves and put into slave labor camps
where they would be worked to death.
Okay, doing whatever mining, digging,
rubber rubber plantation stuff or
whatever. Those children also eventually
died and they, you know, they would they
would have these daily targets for
everybody whatever based on whatever
work they were doing. And if they did
not meet the daily targets, their hands
would be chopped off. Okay? Their hands
would be chopped off. black people's
hands. And to commemorate that in
Belgium there is this this uh Belgian
hands chocolate. Okay.
Hands chocolate.
They uh still sell this. They still sell
this.
Okay.
They still sell this in Belgium. It was
based on what they used to do to these
people. They used to chop off people's
hands. They used to chop off children's
hands.
And the Belgians still celebrate this.
There is something called tune.
Okay.
Which well
it's it's based on the N word in French.
Okay. And these are supposed to
represent the heads of African people.
And when I was a kid in Europe,
it was still called tetan. Today it's
called something else. I think they've
changed the name to make it less
offensive and to kind of hide their
guilt.
But yeah, uh so Leopold I was an utter
brute, a barbarian, a genocidal maniac,
but nobody talks about him. Hitler very
bad. I'm not saying Hitler isn't bad.
Hitler was a monster. Sure. But Hitler
is said to have killed 6 million people.
6 million. This guy Leopold II killed at
least 10 million. But nobody regards
Leopold as a monster. When we talk about
the evilst people of the 20th century or
the past few hundred years, we talk
about Hitler. We talk about Stalin.
Maybe Mao. No one talks about Leopold.
Why is that? Because Leopold killed
nonwhite people.
White people weren't affected. So it
doesn't matter. Non-white people aren't
equal to white people. They used to have
human zoos in Belgium. Have you heard of
the human zoos in Belgium? Let me show
you. Human zoo. Belgium. Belgium has
this horrific history, okay? No one
talks about today. They used to put
children in and people in human zoos and
the white people would stand outside and
watch. I mean, look at this little
child. She's been is being displayed in
a human zoo.
Absolute monstrosity what the Belgians
did.
Absolutely monstrous people.
Okay.
And these human zoos they went on until
I don't know 1958 was it? How long did
this go on? 19th and 20th centuries.
You even had this in the US of course.
That's fantastic. The US also has its
own wonderful history. But we're
discussing Belgium here. The US is a
fantastic nation by the way. They they
lectures lecture us about freedom and
human rights and democracy.
So um so this is what Belgium did.
So the thing is that they did not their
victims weren't white. Their victims
were blacks. Blacks don't matter.
Uh there used to be this you know this
this uh
this this cartoon comic book series
Tintin
uh the the the
creator was who was French Belgian. So
Tintin in Congo
Tintin in Congo. So this is a pretty
racist and pretty nasty thing actually.
I mean, growing up, I was a big fan of
Tintin.
So, most of the Tintin stories are still
great, actually. But Tintin in Congo,
there's a lot of racism in this. I I'll
not go I I'll not bother you with the
details. You can look it up yourself.
What What kind of racism exists in there
pretty Yeah, it was pretty normal for
for those days. I think Tintin in Congo
must have come out in the 1930s.
It was pretty normal to be racist
against black people at the time.
So that that's what happened because the
people weren't white. Hitler killed
people who were mostly white. Even the
the Jewish people at that time I suppose
in Europe were considered to be white
people.
So Hitler evil. Um Stalin killed his own
people who were who well today the
Europeans regard the Russians and
Russians as non-white I suppose Asians
or whatever Asiatics. But back in the
day they were I suppose considered white
and stolen killed white people. That's
why he's slightly bad. He's considered
to be somewhat bad. Not as evil as
Hitler, but still evil.
And uh now no one cares. He killed
Chinese, who cares? Chinese are not
white, so it doesn't matter. So the
thing is, if white people die, then
whoever did that is super evil. If brown
people or Chinese or Eastern Asian
people die, then it's a lesser category
of evil. And if black people are
victimized, no one cares at all,
especially in the West. So that's why no
one cares and nobody bothers to uh you
know paint Leopold II in the same light
as Hitler. He just killed blacks. Who
cares? Now why do Belgians say the
atrocities in the Belgian Congo were
Leopold II's fault and Belgium wasn't
respon responsible for them? Because
it's convenient.
Just blame the guy. I mean all the
Belgian officers and officials and
civilian administrators and all who
oversaw the the bureaucratic execution
of these massacres and this genocide
they don't matter right they were all
just following orders didn't the Nazis
say that we were just following orders
of Hitler right so it's convenient and
because there's been no pressure on
Belgium right see Belgium did this until
the 19 19 1908
1920s 1930s even and then you had the
first World War, the Second World War,
and Belgium then portrayed itself as
this small European nation that was
victimized in the world wars and they
ran with that with that claim. And
that's why they just either
stayed quiet, kept quiet about Bel,
about Congo or said it was the Leopold
II's fault. It's only in the 1990s
onwards that they kind of said, "Okay,
maybe we may have been
not very right in what we did." And
yeah, it is regrettable blah blah blah.
But they would never really apologized
for this. So if you're a white nation,
you can get away with with all these
things.
Okay, we still have more questions.
Okay, what do we have? Rahul Dunak says,
why does it take so much of intellect to
step up from hunting animals to raising
them for food or or graduating from
fruit or vegetable gatherers to
cultivating them? No animal other than
homo sapiens has the ability to
cultivate vegetables and flock animals.
Why does it require so much of brain
power?
So look, if you're a tiger, you look
around. Ah,
go catch it. Eat. If you're a lion,
yeah, there you go. Deer, go catch him.
Eat him. No thinking required. Something
moves, go and catch it and eat it. And
yeah, that sort of thing. If you're a
crocodile, no thinking required.
whatever comes in the river, grab it,
roll over and eat it. Uh, and so on. I
could give hundreds of examples like
that, right? Different species, they all
do that. Hunting species, they hunt,
carnivorous animals and predators. Now,
we were like that. We were predators,
but we were omnivorous. So, during our
huntergatherer days, we didn't have to
think too much, okay? We had primitive
tools, maybe uh spears, maybe whatever
else, and we would just go after
mammoths
uh in the ice the icy regions of the
earth or small prey or whatever. Just
hunt them, kill them, bring them back,
maybe eat them raw, maybe roast them on
a fire and eat it. And u you live from
hand to mouth that way. Sometimes you
would find some fruits or some roots or
whatever, you would eat that. So you had
to move last large large distances just
to get some food and sometimes you would
go hungry seven days of the week there
was no week back in the day but let's
say seven days maybe 5 days you would go
hungry in two days you would eat as much
as possible so whenever you made a big
kill you would feast eat as much as
possible then go hungry the next three
four days and that's how we have evolved
today we eat three meals a day that's
why we are unhealthy
fasting that's why is is good for health
because we have evolved that way now
so you don't need a lot of intelligence
to do that. You just follow that that
pattern. Just look for whatever you can
find. If you can hunt something, kill it
and eat it. And if you can just forage
around and find some roots or fruits or
whatever, you eat that. A lot of it
depends on luck. But then
what our ancestors started doing is they
started observing patterns and cycles
that you take this the seed. I mean I
dropped some seeds there 3 months ago
and today that seed whatever plant or
tree it came from I'm seeing that little
tree growing there it'll eventually
become a big tree. So they started
observing patterns and they started
understanding that seed that the plants
come from seeds.
So if there is this this crop or this
fruit that I like to eat, it's
nutritious. I can just plant its seed
and uh it'll it'll eventually grow into
a plant and eventually if I tend the
plant and water it enough then
eventually it will give me more fruits.
That sort of thing. So that requires
long-term thinking. It requires you know
a chain of thoughts. It requires the
ability to plan and and foresee things
and that requires more brain power than
what um a cat would have I suppose right
so that's cultivation now when it comes
to cultiv cultivating different kinds of
crops once again you understand each
crop is different each crop requires
different kind of climatic conditions
different kind of water watering
patterns different seasons they grow in
different kinds of soils all that stuff
that's pretty complex stuff Right? So
that's why you need more brain power.
More brain power. When it comes to uh
animal agriculture, let's say you you
see this bird that you like to eat, you
know, this is wild bird in the Indian
subcontinent and let's say you capture
it. Instead of killing it, you say,
"Okay, you now stay in this cage and
I'll get you another mate and you going
to you can have eggs together and kids
together and I would like you to grow."
And over thousands of years,
it gives rise to the chicken. The
chicken comes from the Indian
subcontinent. And our ancestors
domesticated the chicken,
right? So for that you have to
understand the life cycle of the bird
and what the bird needs, what what is
bad for the bird and so many so many
more things. So that's why it takes so
much intellect because it's not hunting
is just you know it's it's very
primitive but raising animals and
raising crops and so on it it requires
so much brain power. So that's why
because of all these activities and
actions and stuff we became larger brain
over time. also because we are bipedal
and we can see so much further than
other animals. That's why you know we
gather more information. Um so these are
the things which made homo sapiens what
homo sapiens is today.
All right.
Amisha says why were the Japanese
extremely cruel to the inhabitants of
the countries they invaded? If their
plan was to have satellite states, why
kill millions of civilians? Something
that would obviously cause fierce
resistance against the Japanese
occupation. So it all begins with the
Japanese uh um what they call the uh
major restoration which was the
destruction of the dharmic roots of
Japan. So Japan was a dharmic nation for
for almost 1500 years. The samurai were
were practitioners practitioners of
dharma. Today they are categorized as
Buddhists but many of the gods they
worshiped were Hindu gods. Right? And
their way of life was called the
bushido. That was the samurai way of
life. That is well you could consider it
to be something of a Japanese version of
the chhatria or rajut way of life. That
sort of thing. It was all about honor.
It was all about duty. It was all about
u you know being being honorable and all
that. The way a warrior should live and
the way a warrior should die that sort
of thing. Um and the major restoration
was all about destroying the samurai
system, eradicating that destroying
portrait attempting to destroy to to
eradicate Buddhism, Hinduism from
Japanese culture. When that failed, they
portrayed it as a foreign religion and
so on. And um the the the major
restoration was about making Japan a
clone of the western nations which are
these immoral, barbaric, brutal nations
that destroy entire genocide entire
civilizations. The Japanese said that
you know what we should become like that
otherwise they they will do that to us.
So better us do to everybody else. Uh so
that's what was done and then the
Japanese military in you know it it it
kind of perverted bushido the samurai
way of life. Obviously the samurai were
destroyed but their way of life was kind
of perverted and twisted. So in bushido
in the samurai way of life
you don't surrender. Surrender is
shameful. So if you are captured alive,
first of all, you should not be captured
alive in in a battle. But if you somehow
get captured alive, you have the right
to perform separ
which means you end your life in this
ritualistic manner and by doing that you
re you restore you regain your honor by
you know killing yourself. So in in
samurai culture,
surrender was seen as the ultimately as
the most shameful thing. You don't
surrender. You die a good death in
battle. Or if you're captured, your
enemy who has captured you will give you
the opportunity to commit say puku and
regain your honor. That was the samurai
court. Even among enemies there was
honor. So surrendering was seen as
shameful. So the Japanese military after
destroying the samurai way of life in
the samurai they perverted and twisted
bushido saying that anybody who
surrenders is shameful and doesn't
deserve to live and they applied that
even to civilians.
Now how do you expect civilians to not
surrender? Civilians aren't warriors,
right? The samurai had bushido but only
for the samuris. They never ever just
like in India when when when when the
warriors fought when two armies fought,
they never touched the civilians, right?
Even in Japan, you have the same thing.
The samurai did not ever when they
fought a war, they did not go and harm
civilians.
with the Japanese army after the major
restoration extended bushido or that
perverted twisted bushido to say that
anyone who surrenders is worthless is
dishonorable and you can do whatever you
want with them. The Japanese army's
discipline was brutal
uh routine beatings and humiliation and
all. So extending that to civilians they
had subjugated was just natural and
normal for them. So they were no longer
dharmic. They had moved away from the
original bushido. They regarded any
surrender as shameful and the people who
surrendered as worthless and they were
they were technologically very powerful
which means that they were able to
conquer many nations going westwards
um during the second world war. Their
plan was not to have satellite states.
Their plan was to have subjugated
territories and whichever whichever
nations resisted fiercely, the Japanese
got more frustrated and eventually when
they won they made no difference between
civilians and soldiers and they just did
all kinds of nasty brutalities.
Uh so it was not like they wanted to
have satellite states. what they wanted
to have subjugated states and the more
brutal you are the more you can
subjugate
brutality will not cause fierce
resistance it will break the resistance
that was the logic of the Japanese and
so on so the root cause is Japan moving
away from dharma
moving away from their own culture their
own moral and ethical values and
adopting the morality and ethics of the
western nations that is the root cause
of all the Japanese brutality that we
saw in the after during the second world
war.
Rahul Dunak says why is the American
continent called the new world when we
know that it was inhabited by red
Indians since millennia? Isn't it a bit
derogatory or belittling of the red
Indians? What is Indian in the word red
Indians indicate? Well, today you don't
call them red Indians. It's called It is
not a very polite thing to say. You call
them Native Americans or indigenous
Americans. But a lot of people still
call them red Indians or Indians. Why
are they called Indians first of all or
red Indians? Well, see, first of all,
there if you look at the uh native
people of the Great Plains region and so
on in North America, they have this uh
ruddy appearance, reddish, no reddish
skin tone skin tone. That's why they
were called red red Indians. But why
were they called Indians? It's because
of Columbus. Columbus had had promised
to his patrons, the king and queen of
Spain, that he was going to discover
India by going westwards. And when he
ran into the Bahamas, he imagined he had
discovered India. So he went back and
said, I discovered India and these
people are Indians. And then eventually
the Spaniards and everybody else
realized this is not India. This is a
new place, new continent and so on. But
that term Indians continued when Diego
Armando Maradona played in Napolei Itali
when he was still new when unknown
people used to taunt him Indian because
he had this you know native appearance
Maradona
it's only when he became a superstar
that people stopped calling him Indian
I'm talking about the about the 1980s
here
I think he was taunted as Indian even in
Argentina the go maradona.
Um so yeah so they are called they are
still called Indians because Columbus
initially believed that Columbus
insisted until he died that it was it
was India that he discovered by the way
and and that term Indians just stuck.
Today even the locals call themselves in
Spanish Indos Indians um across the
Americas.
Now why is this continent called the new
world even though it was inhabited by by
natives for millennia? It's because when
the Europeans discover something that's
when it becomes new. I mean the
Europeans discovered India also right?
We have been living in India for I don't
know 80,000 years our people but we were
discovered by the Europeans.
I mean I sometimes can run out run out
of polite things to say about them. So
when the Europeans run into something or
or find something for the first time,
that's when it it is discovered
and obviously that's a new world that
they discovered which nobody knew
existed. So then Eurasia became the old
world. Eurasia and Africa became the old
world and the Americas became the new
world.
It's a all of this is from the European
perspective, Euroentric perspective.
Yeah.
Okay.
Amisha says, "Why is the Roman Empire
Why is it the Roman Empire and not the
Italian Empire?"
You see, okay, that's an interesting
question. So, in the Mediterranean
region, let's go to the map. What's the
Mediterranean Mediterranean region? The
Mediterranean world. In the old days, in
the Mediterranean world, which is this
region, you used to have city states.
Before Rome, you had Athens. You also
had Sparta.
Where can I Oh, here it is. Sparti still
exists. The ruins still exist. You had
Sparta. You had Athens.
Uh what else did you have? I I I'll give
you just two names here. In Greece,
and obviously you eventually had around
700 BC or something around that time
Rome. So those days you did not have
nations or kingdoms or whatever in this
region. You had citystates. Athens and
Sparta are the two um you know famous
ones from Greece and west of Greece
across the Adriatic Sea across the um
Ionian Sea you have this peninsula that
looks like a boat.
Um yeah. So so then you had the
emergence of Rome around 700 BC around
that time. So Rome became a city state
and the people uh it it initially was
just a small territory. The city the the
the nent city and the small territory
around it and that was called Rome and
eventually it expanded and the the
regions that were subsumed into it they
became also part of the city state's
territory that is the territory of Rome.
So at that time there was no nation of
Italy. There was the peninsula called
the Italic peninsula or the it was
called Italia.
It was the name of the peninsula. It was
not the name of the kingdom or the
territory or the empire or whatever. So
the empire eventually it became an
empire. It was called the empire based
out of centered around the city state of
Rome. So it was the Roman empire not the
Italian empire. Eventually what happens
is that you know so during the imperial
period of era of Rome it was always
called the Roman Empire never Italian
empire the Italian empire was just a
geographical term. It was not a cultural
or national or whatever term. It was a
geographical term.
Eventually um and and and after the
demise of the Roman Empire, the Western
Roman Empire, you had all these little
principalities and kingdoms and so on in
um in the region which is now called
Italy and you never had an Italian
empire. It's only in the 19th century
when the uh when the kingdom of Italy
was properly formed for the first time
and they conquered uh let's say what is
it Ethiopia and so on that's when the
term Italian empire u came into being
and today you have the nation state of
Italy so that's why it was always the
Roman Empire never the Italian empire it
the Italian empire was that term was
used only in the 19th and 20th centuries
okay what else do we have uh do we have
more questions. Um,
okay, let's take this one. Ritik says,
"How did the US so successfully occupy
Japan militarily
even when the US had just entered into
the phase of becoming a superpower? So
we imagine that the US becomes starts
becoming a superpower after it defeats
Japan in 1945 which is not the case.
How did the US occupy Japan successfully
militarily? So understand something my
dear friends understand. I'm going to
show you the scale of what the Americans
did. The second world war started in
1939. It ended with the twin American
nuclear tests on Hiroshma Nagasaki in
1945. 19339 to 1945. In 1939, American
military production was very small. But
then this they ramped it up. So from
1939 to 1945,
the Americans produced approximately
300,000
military aircraft. Three lakh military
aircraft
out of which half were destroyed in the
Second World War. How many combat
aircraft, fighter planes, bombers,
attack aircraft, etc.? More than two
lakh fighter planes, combat aircraft
including bombers. Out of these about
one lakh fighter planes and how many
bombers? About one lakh bombers, heavy,
very heavy, strategic, medium, light,
all that bombers.
Three lakh military aircraft were were
built by the by the Americans in just
six years. It's actually in just 5 years
about 90,000 tanks. They built 90,000
tanks out of which about 80,000 survived
the Second World War. Okay. They built
about 130 aircraft carriers.
How many? They built 130 almost aircraft
carriers. The Americans and more than
100 survived the war.
They built between 1,200 to,400 major
warships. And most of these warships
survived the war. The Americans built
more than 200 submarines.
They lost about 50.
But overall, because they already had
submarines before, about 200 submarines
survived the war. So imagine the scale
of what the American military was
capable of.
It was already a superpower.
It was a superpower long before the war
ended.
Okay.
That is what the Americans did.
That's what makes you a superpower.
Obviously, you're going to conquer the
world with that, with that kind of
military might.
That's what it takes to be a superpower,
Vishwaguru, all that nonsense that
Indians love to boast about. You don't
become Vishwaguru and superpower through
slogans.
You have to do put in the hard work. The
Americans did that, didn't they?
Okay. Okay. Um let's take a couple more
questions. Amisha says, "If what if
India had chosen to become an autocracy
like China instead of becoming a
democracy?"
Well, India would have been a visual
guru and superpower. If India had chosen
to be an autocracy like China, so who
would have been the autocrat of India?
It would have been Subashandra Bose.
Subhandra Bose. The question people will
ask that what kind of dictator would he
have been? Would he would he have been
capable of administering a great large
nation like India?
Subashundra Bose I think he came first
in the Indian civil services exam which
is the predecessor of today's IA is so
obviously he was eminently capable of
administering a nation like India he was
eminently capable of commanding an armed
force a massive armed force right so if
he had success if he had successfully
defeated the British and then he would
have become most likely the dictator of
India for about I don't
20 years, 30 years, whatever it was,
they would have been great at that. And
then none of this nonsense would have
happened in India. This colonization,
this this refusal to decolonize India,
this all all this uh reservations based
on cast,
all this all these all this political
nonsense. None of this would have
happened in India. India would have
industrialized massively.
India would have been way ahead of China
today if Subashudra Bose had succeeded
and India had become an autocracy.
India would have none of the problems
India has today. Maybe India and and
some people will say that what about
India would not have been partitioned
then would we not have communal riots
and all that. You think Subashindra will
would have tolerated communal riots
there would have been no issue of
Pakistan or whatever. You would have
crushed any nonsense with an iron fist.
Right? So if India had not chosen but if
India had become an autocracy
in the 1940s, India would be a totally
different beast today, India perhaps
maybe would have would possibly have
been a vish guru and superpower. But
here we are today, this mediocre little
nation.
That's where we are. Okay. Uh Amisha
says, "Why was Christianity more
successful than Roman paganism in the
Roman Empire?
Christianity simply outperformed out
competed Roman paganism. Christianity
had characteristics that no pagan
religion or polytheistic religion has.
Christianity was organized. Christianity
was organized in a military fashion,
top- down command and control structure.
Christianity was a missionary religion.
aggressively missionary religion and
Christianity was an exclusivist religion
and it eventually and it was a political
religion. It captured the power of the
state eventually. Right? Um so
Christianity it it had a single
universal god. My god is the only god.
It had its own doctrine. It had a that
sort of thing. And it had this very
clear idea of what the you know personal
salvation is and so on. And in in
traditional Roman religion, paganism,
you had all kinds of local gods and
local cults that were all amalgamated
together. Reminds you very much of
India, doesn't it? That's what Hinduism
is. All kinds of local customs and and
traditions are all brought into one big
major thing called Hinduism. uh which
has so many different paths and so many
different models of the universe, right?
Christianity claimed to care for the
oppressed which means that it had to
create distinctions between the
oppressors and the oppressed, create
divisions in society and then weaponize
those those distinctions. Right? This
they they they
appealed to slaves, they appealed to
women by portraying women as oppressed.
Eventually Christianity oppressed women
way more than anybody else. But uh it
they claim that we will uplift the poor.
We they claim that we will oppress we
will uplift any any people who are
marginalized
by the by the Roman system, the
aristocratic system, this this unequal
system, this classist cast system. H
we're going to end it all. You know that
sort of thing. And Christianity was like
I said a missionary religion.
aggressively missionary. Um the
Christian missionaries traveled across
Roman roads. They preached everywhere.
They founded communities wherever it was
possible across the empire. The the
unified Roman Empire actually helped
Christianity, right? They could travel
all across the Roman Empire without
having to you know having to face the
problems and difficulties of of crossing
the border of a kingdom and all all
that. Nothing. excellent roads,
excellent excellent uh communications,
excellent transportation,
a single market, a single entity,
empire. So that they use that, they
weaponize that. Um Christianity said
that the worship of Christ is the only
valid worship. Everything else is
satanic and all that, right? Converts,
people who converted were expected to
abandon and destroy and burn and
denigrate their old gods entirely.
Right?
um other
other uh the Roman pagan religion it was
completely soft it was completely non-m
missionary it was non-exclusive you
could worship new gods tomorrow morning
you could add gods to the gods you
worshiped you could bring in bring in a
new statue of a god new morty of a god
you do not have to drop the old ones
let's say in your in your house you are
praying to five gods and you said okay
this new god I've heard about is nice so
let's bring in a morti of that god we'll
now pray to six gods you don't need to
replace old gods, you can add more. In
Christianity, you don't do that, right?
And um so because you could add new gods
and or interchange gods or whatever, the
Roman polytheism did not have any
mechanism to to aggressively poach
souls, poach poach new believers to win
new believers. Nothing. There was no
such thing. There was no competition,
right? Um
and yeah the Roman infrastructure helped
uh
helped Christianity. Uh the Christian
uh system it was organized in military
fashion. You had bishops, you had
councils, you had networks of churches.
They all you know supported each other
and they were rigidly disciplined and so
on. And eventually what happened is that
the the Christians were able to convert
emperor Constantine. He converted to
Christianity and this this gave
Christianity imperial favor and he
started pers then eventually the the
Roman Empire started persecuting the
pagans, the polytheists and all these
Christian uh churchmen, bishops and
whatnot. They started becoming
politically powerful.
Then all the money of the empire was was
poured into building churches, giving
more privileges to the to the cler to
the clergy and so on. Eventually you had
the council of Nika. The ning
Christianity became the official
religion and everybody else was was
persecuted. There was no more official
funding for for polytheistic practices.
Polytheistic practices were forbidden.
Temples were closed. Temples were
destroyed. the statues of old deities
were defaced and mutilated. Even some
practices were even criminalized
and all that. So that's how Christianity
destroyed Roman polytheism.
Cautionary tale.
Yeah. Okay. So that brings me to the end
of today's uh the questions I have
selected. Now let's see. I have 25 super
chats waiting for me. I can see that.
Okay. My request to all of you please
stop taking any more super chats
otherwise this will go on for a very
long time. I will now go through the
super chats that we have. Um Vinit says
was Udai Hussein once a peaceful
nonviolent Gandhian man before power
influenced by Saddam or is that rumor
also why no why was he named Udai?
Was he a peaceful nonviolent Gandhian?
Well I am not aware of any peaceful
nonviolent Gandhian phase of Udai
Hussein's life. um
influenced by Saddam because Saddam was
a peaceful nonviolent Gandhian was he?
Well, I'm not aware of that. Why was he
named Dudai? I don't know.
Um
there are rumors that Saddam Hussein was
of Alzat ancestry, Indian ancestry
possibly. I'm not sure if it's true. So
if there is some Indian connection, some
Indian ancestry, then maybe that's why
he may have given his son an Indian
name. It's all speculation. I don't
know. There have been claims that he had
Saddam Hussein had Indian ancestry, alat
ancestry, Jat ancestry. He did. It does
look like a Jed guy, doesn't he? But we
don't know for sure. We don't know for
sure.
Aayush Gupta says what all could be
potentially wrong steps by the US so
that they would start losing their power
piece by piece in military and economic
military
and economically
potentially wrong steps by the US.
Alienate all your allies. Alienate all
the people who used to be close to you.
Um bully everybody.
All that is fine as long as your
military is powerful and you can you can
enforce your will through military
measures as as long as you can do that
it's fine but if they fall behind in the
technological race with China that could
be an issue if China can become superior
to the US in space for example that
could become an issue because then you
can project power above the earth's
surface in from from earth's orbit that
could be an issue but China is nowhere
near threatening the US hedgemony in
space and India is not even near China's
position. Um so potentially wrong steps
is being complacent in technology.
Allowing China to win the AI race is a
potentially wrong step. Another
potentially wrong step is u you know um
alienating all your allies and creating
co you know forcing them into coalitions
against you. This sort of thing could
eventually down the road uh cause the US
to start losing power. Not anytime soon.
Sid Dave says, "I am a fan, but all
evidence I have seen of Arian migration
seems to be that it's true. Why should
Hindus reject it? Indo-Uropean culture
synthesized with Indis Valley culture
gave birth to Hinduism." Well, that's
your perspective. I have made entire
entire live streams in which I have u in
which I have explained
why it is wrong. I have even written an
article. Uh so I can give you evidence
at the end of the day. It's up to you
whether you want to believe or not. I
will I'm not forcing anybody to believe
what I believe. Okay. Or to even agree
with the evidence I've shown, okay? RN
invasion mates Java.
Um, for example, V we V we V we V we V
we V we V we V we V we V we V we V Ind
India facts. This is the article right?
This is the article from 2017. So it's
an article that's 9 years old now. This
is 2026. But the evidence I've put out
over here it still holds. And all the
new genetic evidence doesn't make any
difference because genetics doesn't
decide culture or language. And the core
claims there are two core claims of the
Arian invasion theory. The first claim
is that Hinduism came from outside of
India. And second claim is that Sanskrit
came out of India. I don't care about
genetics. We are all the whole human
population has mixed genetics. I don't
care about that. So
can anybody prove that Hinduism
originated out outside of India? That is
evidence of arin invasion or migration
is not you saying migration here, right?
Not invasion. So at least you agree it
was not not invasion.
The claim the core central claim hidden
in all this mess is not of genetic
influx into India.
The core claim is twofold that Hinduism
is foreign to India and Sanskrit is
foreign to India. These are the two
claims. I don't care about the genetics
influ genetic influence to India after
2000 BC or whatever. That is okay.
That's fine. What's the evidence it
brought Hinduism and into India? Anyway,
look, I am not here to try and convince
you or whatever. You can check out that
article. You can check out the the ask
kabajit episodes I've done on the arian
invision myth.
But uh if you have decided it's you
believe in so and so thing good luck
sir. I I I'm perfectly happy with you
believing whatever you want to believe.
Entirely fine. All I would say is try
and think critically.
Maybe some things have convinced you and
if it if it's convincing enough for you
well be happy. I wish you the best sir.
Okay. Gora TV says, "Nations like China
possess advanced recognizance and
imaging satellites that can effectively
monitor stealth vectors like the B2,
F-35, etc. in almost real time from
space.
Does it make stealth assets obsolete?"
To some extent it does. See if you have
a network of satellites okay that give
you real time imaging of all the you
know aerial assets that a nation can
deploy
then even if your radars can detect the
thing your satellites are detecting it
and that does kind of to some extent
make stealth less relevant. Obviously
even if your satellite can detect the
stealth aircraft coming in but your
radar can't detect it then how do you
lock onto it and shoot it down? You
can't
you can't right so it doesn't quite make
stealth observatory. Once again if if
it's in nighttime
okay then maybe your satellites can't
detect that at night time or maybe they
they can see in certain in you know
infrared bands or whatever it may in
that case they may be able to find it
but then once again they'll not be able
to pinpoint it exactly and so on. So
there are there are issues you see and
China doesn't have anything like the
kind of satellite coverage the Americans
have.
Um so it does not quite
make the B2 and F-35 and other other
stealth aircraft obsolete. It does give
China let's say early warning.
It does give China the understanding of
where roughly
the aircraft is and where what it's
passing through. But the satellite can't
can't enable the satellite can cannot
enable the the air defense systems to
lock on to the incoming aircraft, right?
So they can't shoot it down even though
the satellite can see it. So it does
give some advantages but doesn't quite
give the ability to to shoot it down.
V4 valor says is cavary engine now ready
for indigenous use? I have no idea. I
have not heard any of any
a major progress. I think some version
some one of the variants of the engine
can be used for drones
uh but not for fighter planes. So I
don't think it's ready for fighter
planes.
Gora TV says, "Can you share any recent
military operation from any can you
share any special military operation
from recent history that you find
particularly impressive?" For me,
Operation Neptune Spear tops the list.
Um,
special military operation from recent
history that I find particularly
impressive.
Neptune spear tops the list for you. Um
uh recent history well recent history
let's say past 25 years okay 21st
century operations
um
not sure
21st century operations military
operations what wars have we had in the
21st century we had the Iraq invasion
2003 we had the Afghanistan thing the
occupation of Afghanistan for 20 years.
Uh do we have any other wars? You have
various conflicts in Africa. You have
Ukraine. I can't think of any recent
military operation that's particularly
impressive, I'm afraid. Uh so yeah, it
looks like I'm not able to think of
anything. Maybe I'm missing something.
Maybe my mind is scrambled right now,
but I'm not able to think of anything.
Sorry. Uh deep learner says, "I don't
understand. And if Trump is aligned with
the deep establishment's interests, then
why did he shut down US aid? That seems
counterintuitive. Well, it's not like
the US had only one option.
Please understand, my dear friends,
shutting down one thing doesn't shut
everything down. US aid was a tool of
the US for interfering in the internal
affairs of other countries. Do you think
it's the only tool the Americans have?
Have you heard of the National Endowment
for Democracy?
Endowment. What is this? What is the
National Endowment for Democracy? It's
another tool of interference in other
nations internal affairs. The Americans
have tens of thousands of NOS's they can
use to infiltrate and interfere in other
countries internal affairs. USA makes no
difference. Maybe there was something in
USA that went counter to the
establishment's interests. The
establishment has tens of thousands of
other options.
Okay.
I see MB says on the Aar Musafer podcast
you talked about lack of ambition in
terms of space. I spoke about that in
2021 on Ren's podcast also.
So it's not like this is something new
that I've come up with. I have been
saying this for years.
So what do India and ISRO need to do
differently in the domain? I don't blame
ISRO at all for this. ISRO simply takes
orders and does what it is ordered to
do. ISRO can't decide I want to take
these five take up these five new
projects that are very ambitious. ISRO
doesn't have the authority to decide
anything. ISRO is a bunch of engineers
who get orders from up top and they
execute the orders with tiny budgets.
That's what ISRO does. ISRO doesn't lack
ambition. The political leadership of
India lacks ambition.
What needs to happen? More funding and
more ambitious projects. We need Okay,
concrete stuff. What is the GSLV's you
know LO payload mass G okay okay LMV3
it's called now whatever it's called
LMV3 what is LMV3 okay launch vehicle
what are the characteristics
uh heavy lift 4,200 kg payload to GS to
geocynchronous or transfer orbit okay uh
what about the Falcon Falcon
Falcon 5 is it Falcon 5 uh Falcon
Space X
Falcon 9. Okay, Falcon 9. What is its
payload capacity? One second.
Falcon 9 payload capacity. Okay, I have
to go into the Wikipedia thing. Quickly,
quickly, quickly, quickly. Mass launch
history, blah blah, etc. Payload to geo
transfer. Okay, 8,300
for the LMV3 is 4,000 something, right?
So, there's like almost double of that.
So we need more powerful rockets.
India needs more powerful rockets. India
needs more satellites. India needs more
space launches.
We need to augment our capabilities. We
need to be able to send Chundrean
mission whichever it is next to the to
the moon in like 5 days instead of
taking three to four months to reach
there.
Right? Because the rockets aren't
powerful enough. So much I can list out
but looks like the political leadership
doesn't have the ambition at all for for
space.
We'll launch five things a year. Two
will fail now. Terrible.
ISRO can be the best space organization
in the world. We have the talent. We
have the potential. We have the brains.
We have everything. We lack the
ambition.
Godliness says, "China and the US are
both going for sixth generation
fighters. Japan and the UK are building
their own stealth AI friendly drones,
but we are still stuck with 114 files
with no money left for AMC or the MK M2.
Beggars can't be choosers.
Yeah,
ideally we should be developing our own
aircraft. We should have been doing that
long, long ago. Right now, we are where
we are. We have this shortfall of
fighter planes.
We need we are way below the number of
fighter planes we need to have. We are
almost on par with Pakistan. Can you
imagine that? A nation like India with a
almost $4.5 trillion GDP. We are almost
on par with Pakistan in terms of fighter
planes. What a shameful situation that
is. Is that who is to blame for this?
The government of India. So now we are
trying to make some kind of stop gap
arrangement deal to get some Rafals but
then there'll be no money left for AMC.
is that I mean it's terrible. So this is
this is mismanagement. This is terrible.
This is terrible.
We have to go all in on the AMCA on the
mark 2.
I think cut down the larly ba yoja or
whatever freebie schemes you're running
and put the money in this right to hell
with your votes. But no, that won't
happen.
Brown Leprechaun says, "Do you think DJ
has boxed him boxed himself into a
corner in in Iran?" No.
How has he boxed himself into a corner?
He has options. He has the option to not
strike and not do anything at all. Just
pressurize. He has the option to take
out
potentially the Iranian top leadership.
He has the option to launch a full-scale
invasion. He has the option to to
destroy all the nuclear facilities of
Iran. He has the option to to to
push in terrorists, ISIS terrorists,
al-Qaeda terrorists from the west and
Pakistani terrorists from the east. He
has all kinds of options with Iran. He's
not boxed himself into a corner.
Uh died with Priosin
says Omar
Beer Putin was FSB chief in 1999 when he
took over president as president of
Russia from Boris Yelin. So was it a FSB
coup against Boris Yelson? It was not of
FSBO against Boris Yelin. Um Putin was
chosen with the approval of Boris Yelson
and Putin had this very steady and and
you know
uh unremarkable track record as a steady
performer
as a guy who was great at obeying orders
and carrying out the things properly. So
it was expected that Putin will be a
great puppet for whoever is is pulling
the strings.
turned out to be totally different. So
it was not a coup against Yelin. Yelin
was way past his prime by the time. He
was drunk all the time. He was not
functioning properly. He was kind of on
the way to becoming Joe Biden. So that's
why they brought in Putin, a young man.
And they expected that Putin will be a
great yes man. Turned out to be exactly
the opposite of that.
Sam the Gamer says, why couldn't Europe
colonize China like India? Takes time.
Takes time. And China was much further
away,
right? The Europeans, when did they come
to India? 1498. The Basod Gama. The
English came to India in 1600,
they were able to actually take India
control of India when after the second
second Anglo Maritime war, the first
half of the 19th century,
18th century,
sorry, 19th
Uh let me just see Anglo second Anglo
Maratha war. When did that happen?
Yeah. Okay. 19th century. So from 1600
to 19 to to to
that's 210 years the Europeans the
British were not able to colonize India.
Right? Do you understand? Look at
history. Look at the chronology. From
1600 to 1810 the British tried after 210
years they were able to colonize India
that just just the process of starting
to occupy India properly that took 210
years they didn't have that sort of time
with China
so that's why didn't work
struggler says thoughts of the new
Epstein files disgusting
these criminals these monsters these
pedophile s rule the United States and
the world and they lecture India about
human rights and freedom and democracy.
Trump has been exposed.
Biden anyway everyone knows what he was.
I mean these people are absolute
monsters
and they have been preaching human
rights to the world.
And I wonder what how come Trump who who
is the president was not able to prevent
this from coming out. His name is not
redacted. It's open.
Looks like he's not in control of his
government. Looks like he's not really
in power. Very interesting. Struggler
says Dr. Bhat Karnad also Dr. Bhat
Karnad says India lacks the will to
power. He also describes how India
should nuclear arm Japan or Vietnam to
counter China. What do I think? what he
has written in is in that book over
here. That book here is the why India is
not a superpower yet or something. That
book is was written 20 years ago.
Why I mean the US won't allow India to
nuclear arm Japan. Does Dr. Barak
Karnner not know that Japan is a US
vasal under US occupation? Does he
imagine that India will be allowed by
the US to give nuclear weapons to Japan?
And what does India gain by giving
nuclear weapons to Japan? what
leverage over China
I mean sir
Vietnam sure but once again if you give
nuclear weapons to Vietnam can do you
really retain control over them
the objective is to give nuclear weapons
to somebody and still retain control
over how they used
it to them and then then let them do
whatever they want. What if they
transfer it to China for some reason? So
I'm not sure about all that stuff.
India definitely lacks the killer
instinct. India definitely has the wrong
system in place. India definitely has
unambitious politicians in place. India
definitely you know
what takes you from 1 to 10 will not
take you from 10 to 100. That's where we
are right now.
The scorpion king says, "Did local
Indian mumines
ever rule any part of India?" Muslims,
you mean? Did local Indian Muslims ever
rule any part of India or did they
simply or they are simply converted
slaves or those who collaborated with
foreign invaders? Uh if you look at the
nisams, if you look at the the the
muggles, if you look at the Delhi
Sultanit, if you look at all these
people, if you look at the the the the
Gores, the Gaznavis,
the only local Indian converted Muslims
who rule India were the Gores
around 1,0 AD or something. So Indian
civilization was whole.
When was the last time our civilization
was whole and undamaged? It was 10,000
AD. It's been a thousand years. So the
the only local converted Indian Muslims
who ruled any part of India were the
Goris
who started ruling Gandhar and then they
made foray into southern parts of India.
The Gaznavids were Turks. The Delhi
Sultanate were Turks. The Muggles were
Turks. Uh the Bengal Sultanate and all
were of course all Turks or Persian
origin. The Nisams were of Turk origin.
The Sha of Gujarat was I think Turic
origin. So apart from the Goris
um no real local Indian has ruled India.
Uh one brief exception is Sher Shasuri
who was of Pashon origin which is of
Indian origin. So he briefly ruled Delhi
for like five years before he blew
himself up and then it gave he
essentially gave it back to the Turks.
So yeah,
Sam the Gamer says, "Can Vietnam be your
Eastern Iran? It's it's role, Vasal."
Nah, it's too early for that. Why would
Vietnam want to be your Vasal?
Why? Nobody decides to be your vasal
unless you give something very very
enticing or you can you force them,
right?
You have to give something very
enticing. If you want Vietnam to be your
vasal, you have to guarantee them
protection from China. Plus economic
incentives and whatn not. So India
forget about Vietnam. You can't even
make Sri Lanka your vasal right now. You
can't even make East Pakistan or West
Pakistan your Wasal. We're talking about
Vietnam. Step by step, right? Let's
first take the baby steps of them all.
We can't even make Nepal our Wasal.
We're talking about Vietnam. Come on.
Um Sri Ram infobe says why India did not
select source code deal for Rafal.
It was not on the table. They must have
asked for it. See first of all the Rafal
deal has not been signed yet. It's not
signed. I don't know what your godamned
Indian media is reporting and what your
bloody YouTubers are reporting. No deal
has been signed thus far. Nothing has
been finalized.
the Sukoy deal is still on the table.
So let's wait. Uh there are all kinds of
reports that the French are saying no to
the source code deal or what source code
or whatever. Let's wait and watch. India
India should demand access to the source
code.
We already operate the Rafale which
means it it makes sense to get more
Rafals but we should say if we are
buying 114 we also want the source code.
We want everything. Push for it. see how
far you can push. Let's see. So, it's
not yet signed.
Gorat TV says, "How would present day
Bat look if the Morin Empire guided by
Ashoka's mindset had not fallen and had
thwarted the Mgul and British invasion?"
Look, how long does an empire typically
last historically, globally speaking?
About 200 to 250 years, 300 years. Some
empires last longer. The Chola Empire,
the Chola dynasty lasted more than a
thousand years, more than 1500 years
actually. Uh the west the eastern Roman
Empire lasted what a thousand plus
years. Yeah. Some empires last long. The
Moran Empire began 2300
BC roughly.
If
it had lasted until the British
invasion, it would have had to last
more than 2,000 years. I would imagine
that's that would be a world record.
But if it had lasted and Ashoka's
mindset had guided us and all that, how
would Bat look like? Bat would look very
free. Bat would perhaps look very
Buddhist, which I'm not sure is what
everybody wants today. But okay, better
than something else. I suppose yeah,
India would have been free. I was I
suppose India would be civilizationally
whole, undamaged, untainted by foreign
nonsense.
Definitely better.
Shin Ram says which may rally platinum,
copper, titanium, bodium. I have no
idea. Can't say. Simply a weeb says did
the first invasion happen before because
we were too kind. First invasion. Which
which first invasion?
Invasions don't happen because because
you're kind. Invasion happen invasions
happen because you're stupid or you're
weak.
Right? That's why invasions happen.
Well, kindness is a form of stupidity
when it is applied to the wrong people.
So, but I'm not sure which first
invasion you're asking me about, so I
can't say. You give me a specific
invasion, then I can answer. Okay. Cyber
SE alien has become a new member. Well,
thank you so much and welcome to the
membership of the channel. Thank you.
Shriam Infoch Infobtech says, "Are
British monarchy plus Vatican real deep
state?" I doubt it.
It may have some components
but not the entire deep state for sure.
Restore Barat says will India allow dual
citizenship? OCI isn't enough. I don't
think India will allow dual citizenship.
I look
dual citizenship is something you can
allow only with vasal states. The US
allows all kinds of nations to have dual
I mean the US allows dual citizenship
for all nations I suppose except for
Russia or whatever right can you be a
dual US-Russia citizen
uh can you be a dual USRussia citizen
can you it's possible is possible yes
Russia is not official but the US allows
that so the US is confident that if you
have dual citizenship, you will always
be
um
loyal more to the US or whatever. That
only happens when you are the most
powerful country in the world. If you're
a nation like India which can't even
vaselize its own neighbors and you allow
dual citizenship, then that will be
typically used against you. So I don't
think India will allow dual citizenship,
it would be great for the people but bad
for the country. I know OCI isn't enough
and you don't get enough benefits and
all that but these are the constraints
India is under. So I I I I feel you, but
I don't think it'll happen.
Um I'm not sure how to read that. My
cirillic is tremendously rusty. So I'm
not sure if if it's this is the right
place to ask for self-help. I'm 27 and
hate myself. I'm trying to quit bad
habits and improve myself. I stay
disciplined for only a few days. Then I
fall back and feel discouraged. Need
guidance.
Okay, you're 27. you are not a very big
fan of yourself right now because you
are not disciplined. You're trying to
quit bad habits. Yeah. The thing is if
you have some bad habits, let's say some
kind of addiction or whatever and you
don't like it, you know it's not good
for you, but it's got its claws deep
inside you. It makes you feel bad about
yourself. I'm pretty sure, right? You
know it's a bad habit. Let's say it's
alcohol or whatever. You know it's not
good for you. It makes you feel terrible
next morning. But you can't quit. So
you're doing something that you hate the
next morning. You know it's not good for
your health, but you can't quit it.
That's why you you hate yourself. I
know.
So
um and you're able to be disciplined for
a few days. I'm just giving alcohol as
an example. There are all kinds of other
things. No, it could be a bad habit. Uh
so you stay disciplined for a few days.
Then you fall back and feel discouraged,
need guidance.
I I think you need professional guidance
actually because I don't know exactly
what your specifics are. Um do you have
family support?
Do you have a good job? Do you have a
good income?
Um what your past life is like? What
what what's your background?
There's so many questions I would need
the answers to before I can actually
give any kind of advice to you.
I would be happy to help you if but I
don't know you personally without
knowing you personally and understanding
your
specific story and the journey that
you've taken I can't offer you any
specific help at all I can only offer
you generic help that don't help
yourself that don't don't hate yourself
okay hate the habit don't hate yourself
it's not a character flaw maybe it's
something else. Maybe it's the if it's a
it's a chemical thing, it's a chemical
that's got a hold of you or whatever. Uh
and you if it's like this, I would say
you need professional guidance and help.
Maybe if it's an addiction, you need a
addiction counseling or something or
Yeah. So without knowing specifically
what the thing is and your entire
specific story, I can't really offer you
help. So I would say don't hate
yourself.
It's definitely possible to get out of
whatever it is and and get your life on
track. I would only recommend this that
you need to get professional guidance.
All right, sir. All the best. Do well. I
wish you the best. I wish you success.
Okay. A Rahul says, "I read about a
Buddhist deity Aokhwara. He or she
multiple incarnations is popular in East
Asia and is said to be the creator of
Shiva, Vishnu, Sarasati, etc. subtle way
of looking down on Hindus.
I suppose yes.
I mean how can a Buddhist deity be the
creator of Shiva, Vishnu, Sarasati, etc.
Buddhism came much later, right?
So um
yeah,
you could you could be correct in what
you're saying. Yes.
Mcllin says, "Is the Modi brand dead
now?"
not quite dead not quite
but uh there are issues for sure right
the recent things and all UGC etc I mean
overall geopolitically India is doing
great India is making the right choices
but internally there are issues so I
think uh a little bit of
changing up is needed and of course
how long can a leader be the leader
how long can you be useful to the
country.
It's all about the see leadership is
about service. Leadership is about
being useful to your people to your
constituency.
So eventually every nation whenever it
is has to make the transition to a new
leader. Is that the time now? I'm not
sure if it is right now. I'm I would not
say the Modi brand is dead as of now,
but it definitely needs some work.
Raja Lakshmi Dash says, "I have a
question to which I'm not able to get an
answer. My question is why are there no
major temple ruins from the Morian
period despite roy strong royal
patronage of the region? The Morian
period
the temples would all have been in
northern and western India
and eastern India which is partly put
through that region. All of these parts
of India came under Turk occupation.
The Turks, they are famous for
destroying temples.
Is there a single great temple that's
still standing in northern western India
or even eastern India? Everything has
been flattened. That's your answer, sir.
That's your answer.
Okay. Pole says the UAE is making the
partnership with India and also partner
of Israel while Saudi Arabia is okay.
it's inclined towards hostile nations
like Pakistan and Turkey. Can you please
explain why Saudi is going on this path?
See Saudi Arabia um it underwent a
leadership u leadership uh
transition
about a decade ago close to a decade ago
uh when Mr. Muhammad bin bin Salman
became the de facto uh ruler of the
country. Prince Muhammad bin Salman and
he had this great vision of a modern
developed progressive Saudi Arabia that
would no longer rely only on uh fossil
fuels for its uh revenue and growth.
and he came up with his big projects
right the neom city the line city the
the cubicle city and all those big big
big fantastic projects those haven't
worked out very well
and uh he has tried to liberalize the
population give women more rights and
all but the population maybe is not very
very strongly inclined towards those
things so looks like these initiatives
are not going well
so what do you do you default
to the nation's uh default settings.
You align with Pakistan and Turkey.
Those are two fundamentalist nations.
Both are terrorist nations. I mean
Turkey
supports Pakistan which is which is a
terrorist nation. And Turkey does
fantastic things like aligning with ISIS
which is terrorists and trying to wipe
out the Kurs which is terroristic
activity, genocidal activity, trying to
wipe out Armenia which is again
genocidal activity. So you could say
these are both terrorist nations.
So Saudi Arabia has decided that okay it
doesn't work out. We'll align with the
terrorists.
That's what's happening.
Those plans did not really work out
well.
Plans of modernizing liberalizing all
that. They tried but that takes
tremendous execution for such a big
transformation of the country. Maybe the
population isn't ready for that. The
quality of the population depends on the
quality of an education system. I'm not
sure what kind of education system Saudi
Arabia has.
So yeah, that's where Saudi Arabia is
today.
Currencies is economic breakdown coming.
Good assets to hold. I am not an
economic adviser. I would not be able to
tell you. I hope there is no economic
breakdown coming. But there could be
economic volatility coming up
potentially. But this is not investment
advice or any such thing.
Okay. S the gamer says, "Explain
geopolitics from Vietnam's perspective."
That would take at least 15 20 minutes.
I'll tell you in brief. Vietnam wants to
remain this independent nation. It wants
to remain a comm kind of communist
nation with um capitalistic tendencies.
It is very scared of China because China
is very evil, very naughty, very
hegemonic, very bullish. China claims
Vietnamese territory and islands and uh
Vietnam wants to remain as balanced as
independent as possible. That's why it's
trying to be friends with the US and
also with India. The main threat from
Vietnam's perspective is China. Vietnam
just wants to mind its own business and
live a nice life. But China won't allow
this to happen. And China has a long
history of interfering in Vietnam's
internal affairs more than a thousand
years old such history. So that's
geopolitics from Vietnam's perspective.
Rahul has become a new member. Thank you
very much, Rahul G. and welcome to the
channel's membership.
Rahul says, "What's with Modi's alleged
name in Epin files?" I haven't seen
that. I'm not aware of it. Sorry.
I haven't seen that. I'm not aware. Is
it really? I don't think so. Okay. I
could be wrong, of course, but I have
not seen that. So, can't say I'll check
it out if if it it it is indeed the
case. All right, people. Thank you very
much for all your questions. I think
I've done dealt with all the super
chats. Thank you so much. This was great
fun and I look forward to seeing you in
tomorrow's live stream in which I will
take all the questions from the super
chat. We'll discuss any topic that you
want. Until then, please take care of
yourselves. Keep learning, keep asking
questions, keep raising your standards.
I'll see you tomorrow. Bye-bye.